You did a wonderful job. Wonderful.
干得漂亮！太棒了！
You did it. You did it!
你做到了！你做到了！
To continue, you've listened to a long and complex case, murder in the first degree.
漫长复杂的审理程序已经结束 这是一宗一级谋杀案
Premeditated murder is the most serious charge tried in our criminal courts.
预谋杀人在刑事诉讼中 是最重的罪名
You've listened to the testimony, had the law interpreted as it applies in this case.
你们都听过了证词 也懂得法律条文的规定
It's now your duty to sit down and try and separate the facts from the fancy.
现在你们的责任是坐下来 好好厘清这宗案子的真伪
One man is dead. Another man's life is at stake.
本案已有一人身亡 另一人的生死掌握在你们手中
If there's a reasonable doubt in your minds as to the guilt of the accused -
如果你们无法确认被告有罪...
a reasonable doubt-then you must bring me a verdict of not guilty.
也就是有了合理的怀疑 那么你们必须做出无罪的判决
If there's no reasonable doubt, then you must, in good conscience,
如果你们找不出合理的怀疑 那么你们必须基于良知...
find the accused guilty.
判决被告有罪
However you decide, your verdict must be unanimous.
然而不论判决如何 你们各位的决定必须一致
In the event that you find the accused guilty,
如果你们裁定本案被告有罪
the bench will not entertain a recommendation for mercy.
本庭将会对他施以严厉的惩罚
The death sentence is mandatory in this case.
对本案来说也就是死刑
You are faced with a grave responsibility. Thank you, gentlemen.
这是一项沉重的责任 谢谢各位
The alternate jurors are excused.
后备陪审员可以退席
The jury will now retire.
陪审团请退席
- Wanna piece of gum? - No, thanks.
- 来块儿口香糖吗？ - 不，谢了
This thing isn't movin'.
这玩意儿卡住了
- I'll give you a hand. - That's it.
- 等我帮你 - 搞定了
You know somethin'? I called the Weather Bureau this morning.
知道吗？ 今早我打电话问过气象局
This is gonna be the hottest day of the year.
今天将是今年最热的一天
You'd think they'd air-condition this place.
我还以为这儿会有空调
- What is your name, sir? - Oh, it's... that one. Yeah.
- 先生，请问尊姓大名？ - 哦，是...是这个，对
Thank you very much. OK, gentlemen. Everybody's here.
非常感谢 好了，先生们。大家都到齐了
Now, if there's anything you want, I'll be right outside the door. Just knock.
现在，如果你们有任何需要 请尽管敲门，我就在外面
Good morning. I never knew they locked the door.
早上好 我不知道他们会锁门
Sure they lock the door. What'd you think?
他们当然会锁门 你以为他们会怎么做？
I don't know. It just never occurred to me.
我不知道 我只是从来没想过有这种事
- What's that for? - I thought we might wanna vote by ballot.
- 那是干嘛的？ - 我想我们可能需要投票表决
Great idea. Maybe we can get him elected senator.
好主意 也许我们该选他当议员
- How'd you like it? - I don't know. It was pretty interesting.
- 你觉得怎么样？ - 我不知道，挺有趣的
- Yeah? I almost fell asleep. - I mean, I've never been on a jury before.
- 是吗？我差点就睡着了 - 我是说，我从来没当过陪审员
No? I've sat on many juries.
是吗？我有很多次经验了
Those lawyers talk and talk, even when it's an open-and-shut case like this one.
不论案子如何显而易见 律师们总是不停地说，就跟这个案子一样
- Ever hear so much talk about nothin'? - I guess they're entitled.
- 你听过那么多没意义的话吗？ - 我想那是他们的工作
They're entitled. It's the system, but...
一点都没错，这就是司法系统 但是...
if you ask me, I'd slap those tough kids down before they start any trouble.
如果要我说，我更乐意先把那帮熊孩子拍死 而不是等他们惹事生非
It saves a lot of time and money. Let's get started.
这会帮我们省下时间跟金钱 开始裁决吧
Yeah. We've probably all got things to do here.
是啊 我们还有很多工作要做
We can start with a five-minute break. One gentleman is in the bathroom.
先等一下 有位先生还在洗手间
Are... we gonna sit in order?
我们...我们按顺序坐吗？
Gee, I don't know. I guess so.
天啊，我不知道 我想是吧
- Buddy, you're in my seat. - Oh, excuse me.
- 老兄，你坐到我的位置了 - 哦，抱歉
That's all right.
没关系
Hey, that's not a bad view, huh?
嘿，风景真不错，是吧？
What did you think of the case? I mean, it had a lot of interest for me.
你对这个案子怎么看？ 我是说，对我来说很有趣
No real... dead spots. You know what I mean?
一点都...不无聊 了解我的意思吧？
We were lucky to get a murder case. I figured us for an assault or burglary.
能遇上谋杀案真是好运气 我还以为我们会遇上伤害案或是盗窃案
Boy, they can be the dullest!
天啊，那可真是无聊
- Hey, is that the Woolworth Building? - That's right.
- 嘿，那不是伍尔沃斯大楼吗？ - 没错
Isn't that funny? I've lived here all my life. I've never been inside it.
真可笑，我从小到大都住在纽约 却从来没去过那里
If you had to sort out all that junk, like that thing with the movies.
你们得抽丝剥茧地把案情弄清楚 就跟电影里演的一样
Yeah. What about that business with the knife?
对 关于凶刀你有什么看法？
Asking grown-up people to believe that kind of jazz.
他们竟要我们这些成年人 去相信那种鬼话
You expect that. You know what we're dealing with.
我一点都不觉得意外 你知道我们面对的是什么样的事情
Yeah, I guess so.
是的，我想也是
Well, your horn works. Now try your lights.
好了，喇叭正常了 现在再试试灯光
- You got a cold? - And how. Hot-weather colds can kill you.
- 你感冒了？ - 是啊，而且热伤风真是要人命
I can hardly touch my nose. Know what I mean?
只要我一摸鼻子就疼得不行 你懂吧？
Sure do. I just got over one.
我了解 我感冒刚好
- Oh, come on! Mr Foreman, let's go. - The guy's still in the bathroom.
- 哦，快点吧，团长先生！该开始了 - 那家伙还在洗手间里
What's new? I didn't get a chance to see a paper this morning.
有什么新闻？ 我还没顾上看报纸
I was only wondering how the market closed.
我只想知道今天的收盘股指是多少
- You got a seat on the exchange? - I'm a broker.
- 交易所有你的席位吗？ - 我是个股票经纪人
I run a messenger service.
我开了一间传呼公司
The Beck and Call Company.
贝克传呼公司
The name is my wife's idea.
名字是我太太起的
Got 37 men workin'. Started with nothin'.
我白手起家，现在雇了37个人
OK, men. Let's take our seats, huh?
好了，先生们 让我们赶紧坐下吧
We can all get out of here pretty quick. I have tickets to that ball game tonight.
我们很快就能离开这儿了 我已经买好今晚的球赛门票了
Yanks and Cleveland. We've got this kid Modjelewski in there.
洋基队对克利夫兰队 Modjelewski会上场
He's a real bull, this kid. You know...
这家伙是头真正的公牛 知道吗...
Real jug-handled. You know?
所向无敌 知道吗？
You're a real baseball fan, aren't ya? Where do we sit here?
你真的是个棒球迷吧？ 我们坐在哪儿？
I thought we'd sit in order, by jury numbers.
我想我们应该 按照陪审团编号就坐
One, two, three and so on around the table, if that's OK with you gentlemen.
一、二、三以此类推环着桌子坐 如果你们同意的话
- What's the difference? - It's reasonable to sit in order.
- 有什么区别呢？ - 听起来合理些
- Let it be. - That's twelve. We go around one, two...
- 就这么办吧 - 那是十二号。我们按顺时针一、二...
What was your impression of the prosecuting attorney?
你对检察官印象如何？
- I beg pardon? - I thought he was really sharp,
- 你说什么？ - 我觉得他很尖锐
the way he handled all those points one by one, in logical sequence.
一个接一个地提出观点 前后非常有逻辑
- I was very impressed. - I think he... he did an expert job.
- 让我印象深刻 - 我觉得他...他做得不错
A lot of drive, too. You know? Real drive.
也非常有干劲儿。知道吗？真有干劲儿
OK, fellas. Can we hold it down a minute? Fellas?
好了，伙计们 把手边的事放一放
Say, we'd like to get started.
我们准备开始了
Gentleman at the window.
窗户边的先生
- We'd like to get started. - Oh, I'm sorry.
- 我们准备开始了 - 哦，抱歉
- The kid kills his father, just like that. - Listen, it happens all the time.
- 那孩子杀了他父亲，很奇怪吧？ - 听我说，这种事常发生
They let those kids run wild up there.
养子不教父之过
Well, maybe it serves him right. You know what I mean?
也许那是他活该 懂吗？
- Is everyone here? - The old man is inside.
- 大家到齐了吗？ - 那老头还在洗手间
- Would you knock on the door for him? - Yeah.
- 麻烦你去喊他过来吧？ - 没问题
- Are you a Yankee fan? - No, Baltimore.
- 你是洋基队球迷吗？ - 不，我是巴尔的摩队球迷
Baltimore?
巴尔的摩？
That's like being hit in the head with a crowbar once a day.
那个队的球员们就像是每天 都要被铁锹敲上一记
Who have they got? Who have they got besides good groundkeepers?
他们有哪些好球员？ 除了外野手还不错
- Say, we'd like to get started. - Forgive me, gentlemen.
- 我说，我们要开始了 - 抱歉，先生们
- I didn't mean to keep you waiting. - Baltimore?
- 我不是故意要你们等我 - 巴尔的摩？
OK, if I can have your attention. You fellas can handle this thing any way you want.
好，各位请听我说 这件事你们想怎么做都可以
I'm... you know, I'm not gonna make any rules.
我是说...你知道... 我是说我不打算制定任何规则
We can, well, discuss it first, then vote on it. That's, of course... that's one way.
我们可以，比方说，先讨论再投票 因为这是一种可行的办法
And, well, we can vote on it right now.
当然了，我们也可以直接投票表决
I think it's customary to take a preliminary vote.
我想依照惯例 我们得先进行假投票
Yeah, let's vote. Who knows? Maybe we can all get outta here.
好极了，我们来投票吧。谁知道呢 也许我们可以立即离开这儿
OK. Then I think that you know that we have a first-degree murder charge here,
好的。我想大家都知道 我们面对的是一宗一级谋杀案...
and if we vote the accused guilty, we've got to send him to the chair.
如果我们判决被告有罪 那等于是送他坐电椅
Um... That's mandatory.
呃...那是必然的结果
- I think we know that. - Yeah, let's see who's where.
- 我想我们都知道 - 是啊，现在来表决吧
- OK. Anyone doesn't wanna vote? - It's fine with me.
- 好的。有人反对进行表决吗？ - 我没意见
OK, then, just remember that this has to be twelve to nothing, either way.
好的。记住，不论判决如何 我们12个人都必须达成一致
That's the law. OK, are we ready?
那是法律的规定 好了，准备好了吗？
All those voting guilty, please raise your hands.
认为他「有罪」的人 请举手
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
一、二、三、四、五、六、七...
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
八、九、十、十一
OK, that's eleven guilty.
好的，11票「有罪」
Those voting not guilty?
认为他「无罪」的人呢？
One. Right.
1票。好的
Eleven guilty, one not guilty. Well, now we know where we are.
11票有罪，1票无罪 嗯，至少我们现在有结论了
Boy, oh boy! There's always one.
天啊！总是会出现唱反调的人！
So, what do we do now?
那么，我们现在该怎么办？
- I guess we talk. - Boy, oh boy!
- 我想我们得好好讨论一下 - 天啊！
You really think he's innocent?
你真觉得他是无辜的？
- I don't know. - You sat in court with the rest of us.
- 我不知道 - 你跟我们一样坐在法庭里
You heard what we did. The kid's a dangerous killer.
你跟我们看到的一样 那孩子是个危险的杀手
- He's 18 years old. - Well, that's old enough.
- 他才18岁大啊 - 他已经够大了
He stabbed his own father four inches into the chest.
他用刀刺入父亲胸口 把他给杀了
They proved it a dozen different ways in court.
对此 他们在法庭上证明了无数遍
- Would you like me to list 'em for you? - No.
- 你想要我跟你一一列举吗？ - 不必了
- Then what do you want? - I just want to talk.
- 那你想干嘛？ - 我只是想谈谈
What's there to talk about? Eleven of us think he's guilty.
有什么好谈的？ 我们有11个人认为他有罪
No one had to think about it twice except you.
没有人对此怀疑 除了你
I want to ask you something. Do you believe his story?
我想问你个问题 你真的相信他的话？
- I don't know. Maybe I don't. - So how come you voted not guilty?
- 我不知道。也许我不相信 - 那你为什么要投「无罪」
There were eleven votes for guilty.
有11票都认为他有罪
It's not easy to raise my hand and send a boy off to die without talking about it first.
送这个孩子坐电椅却不先讨论一下 这让我真的很难举手表决
- Well, now, who says it's easy? - No one.
- 谁说这很容易了？ - 没人
What? Just because I voted fast? I honestly think the guy is guilty.
什么？就因为我举手太快了吗？ 我是真心觉得那孩子有罪的
Couldn't change my mind if you talked for 100 years.
就算你谈上一百年 也无法改变我的决定
I'm not trying to change your mind. It's just that...
我不想改变你的想法 这只是...
This is somebody's life. We can't decide in five minutes.
只是因为我们的判决攸关一条人命 我们不能草草了事
- Supposing we're wrong? - Supposing this building fell on my head?
- 假设我们错了呢？ - 假设我们错了！你不如假设这房子塌了砸到我头？
- You can suppose anything. - That's right.
- 什么事都能假设 - 一点没错
What's the difference how long it takes? Supposin' we take five minutes? So what?
花多少时间讨论又有什么区别呢？ 就算我们只讨论了五分钟，又怎么了？
Let's take an hour. The ball game doesn't start till eight o'clock.
我们可以花一小时讨论 球赛八点才开始
- Who's got something to say? - /'m willing to sit for an hour.
- 谁有意见？ - 只一小时的话，我没意见
- Great. I heard a good story last night... - That's not why we're sitting here.
- 好极了！我昨晚听到个有趣的八卦... - 那不是我们坐在这里的原因
All right, then you tell me. What are we sitting here for?
好啊，那你倒告诉我 我们为什么坐在这儿？
I don't know. Maybe no reason.
我不知道，也许没原因
Look, this kid's been kicked around all of his life.
瞧，这孩子老是被人踢来踢去
You know, born in a slum, mother dead since he was nine.
你知道吗，他生在贫民窟 九岁时母亲去世
He lived for a year and a half in an orphanage
他在孤儿院待过一年半
when his father was serving a jail term for forgery.
因为当时他父亲伪造文书被判入狱
That's not a very happy beginning.
他是先天不良
He's a wild, angry kid. That's all he's ever been. And you know why?
他是个暴戾的野孩子 那就是曾经的他，你知道为什么吗？
Cos he's been hit on the head by somebody once a day, every day.
因为每天都会有人打他
He's had a pretty miserable 18 years. I think we owe him a few words, that's all.
他过了悲惨的18年 我觉得我们应该给他一个机会
I don't mind telling you this, mister. We don't owe him a thing. He got a fair trial.
我不介意这么跟你说，先生，我们什么都不欠他 他得到了公平的审判，不是吗？
What do you think that trial cost? He's lucky he got it. Know what I mean?
你知道这场审判要花掉多少钱？ 他有这样的机会就够幸运了，懂吗？
Look, we're all grown-ups in here. We heard the facts, didn't we?
瞧，大家都是成年人 我们都听到过事实，对吧？
You're not gonna tell me we're supposed to believe this kid, knowing what he is.
不用你来告诉我 怎样假定这孩子是个什么样的人
I've lived among them all my life.
听着，我经常跟他们打交道
You can't believe a word they say. You know that. I mean, they're born liars.
他们说的话，一个字你都不能信 你知道的，我的意思是，他们一生下来就是骗子
- Only an ignorant man can believe that. - Now, listen...
- 只有无知的人才会相信这些话 - 听我说...
Do you think you were born with a monopoly on the truth?
你觉得你一生下就代表着真理吗？
Certain things should be pointed out to this man.
看来我们得教这位先生不少事
- It's not Sunday. We don't need a sermon. - We have a job to do. Now let's do it.
- 这可不是安息日，我们不需要听你训话 - 我们还有个案子要判决，快弄完它吧
Rice Pops. It's a product I work on at the agency.
这是爆米花。 我的公司负责推销这种产品
"The breakfast with the built-in bounce."
「天生充满活力的早餐」
- I wrote that line. - Very catchy.
- 这句广告词是我想的 - 非常传神
- Say, do you mind? - I'm sorry. I have this habit of doodling.
- 请专心 - 抱歉。我有随手乱画的习惯
- It keeps me thinking clearly. - We have work to do.
- 这能让我思维更加清晰 - 我们还有事情要做
There's no point staying here for ever. OK.
没有必要把时间耗在这儿 好
Perhaps if the gentleman down there who is disagreeing with us could tell us why.
也许坐在那边那位 不同意我们意见的先生，能告诉我们原因
Tell us what you're thinking. We might be able to show you where you're mixed up.
告诉我们你怎么想的 也许我们能告诉你，你哪里弄错了
Maybe this is an idea. It seems to me that it's up to us to convince this gentleman
也许我有个好主意 我觉得我们应该轮流来说服这位先生
that he's wrong and we're right. Maybe if we each took a couple of minutes just to...
指出他的错误和我们的正确 也许我们每人拿出一小点时间来...
- Well, it was just a quick idea. - No, no, no. That's a good one.
- 当然了，这想法仓促了点儿 - 不、不、不，这想法很好
Supposing we go once around the table?
我们就照座次一一发言吧？
I guess you're first.
我想应该从你先开始
It's hard to put into words.
这真的很难说出个为什么
I just think he's guilty.
我就是觉得他有罪
I thought it was obvious from the word go. Nobody proved otherwise.
我是说，从证词来看一切非常明显 没有人能证明他无罪
Nobody has to prove otherwise. The burden of proof's on the prosecution.
没有人需要证明他无罪 该证明他无罪的是检察官
The defendant doesn't even have to open his mouth. That's in the Constitution.
被告不必发言 那是宪法赋予的权利
Sure, I know that. What I meant was...
当然，我知道 我的意思是...
Well... I just think he's guilty. I mean, somebody saw him do it.
好吧...我就是觉得他有罪 我是说，毕竟有目击者看到他杀人了
OK. Here's what I think. And I have no personal feelings about this.
好。这是我的想法 对本案我没有任何个人偏见
I just wanna talk about facts.
我只想谈谈事实
Number one.
第一：
The old man lived downstairs under the room where the killing took place.
住在案发现场楼下的那位老人
At 10 minutes after 12 on the night of the killing, he heard loud noises.
凶案发生的当晚12点10分 他听到很大的叫嚷声
Said it sounded like a fight.
他说听起来像是争吵
And he heard the kid yell out "I'm gonna kill ya."
而且他听到那孩子大叫着说 「我要杀了你」
A second later, he heard a body hit the floor.
1秒钟后 他听到有人摔倒的声音
Ran to the door, opened it up, saw the kid run down the stairs and out of the house.
他快步跑到门口，打开门 看到那孩子跑下楼梯，出了公寓
Called the police. They found the old man with the knife in his chest.
他打电话报警 警方发现死者胸口插了一把刀
The coroner fixed the time of death around midnight.
法医推测死亡时间 大约是午夜
Now, these are facts. You can't refute facts. The kid is guilty.
瞧，这些都是事实 你无法拒绝事实。这孩子有罪
I'm just as sentimental as the next fella. I know he's only 18.
我跟其他人一样有同情心 我知道这孩子只有18岁
- But he's still gotta pay for what he did. - I'm with you.
- 但他还得为所作所为付出代价 - 我同意你的说法
- OK. Are you finished? - Yeah.
- 好，你说完了吗？ - 是的
It is obvious to me that the boy's entire story was flimsy.
对我来说，很明显那孩子的整套说词 全是胡说八道
He claimed he was at the movies,
他声称案发时他在看电影...
yet he couldn't remember the names of the films he saw or who played in them.
但他却完全记不起电影跟演员的名字
- That's right. - And no one saw him at the theatre.
- 没错 - 而且没人在电影院看到过他
And the woman across the street-if her testimony don't prove it, nothing does.
听着，还有街对面那位女士 要是她的证词都不算有力，还有谁的算？
- That's right. She actually saw the killing. - Fellas, please. Let's go in order.
- 对。事实上她目击了案发过程 - 伙计们，请大家按顺序发言
Just a minute. Here's a woman...
等一下，案发时这位女士...
Here's a woman who's lying in bed. She can't sleep. She's dyin' with the heat.
这位女士躺在床上 她热得睡不着觉。懂吗？
She looks out the window, and right across the street
总之，她透过窗子向外看 正巧看到...
she sees the kid stick the knife into his father.
这孩子将刀插进他父亲胸口
The time is 12.10 on the nose. Everything fits.
时间无疑是12点10分 一切都吻合
She's known the kid all his life.
瞧，她非常熟悉那个孩子
His window is opposite hers across the el tracks. She swore she saw him do it.
那孩子家跟她家只隔了一条电车铁轨 他发誓说她看到那孩子杀人了
Through the windows of a passing el train.
透过急驰而过的电车车窗？
This el train had no passengers on it. It was just being moved downtown.
对。这辆电车当时没有乘客 它正要开到市区
The lights were out, and they proved in court that at night
当时车上灯光全暗，记得吗 律师证明透过电车车窗...
you can look through the windows and see what's happening on the other side.
可以看到另一边的景象
- They proved it. - I'd like to ask you something.
- 他们已经证明这点了 - 我想问你个问题
You don't believe the boy. How come you believe the woman?
你不相信那孩子的话 为什么却相信那位女士的话呢？
She's one of "them" too, isn't she?
她跟律师们站在同一边 不是吗？
- You're a pretty smart fella, aren't ya? - OK, gentlemen. Now, gentlemen.
- 你以为自己很聪明，对吧？ - 好了，先生们。好了，先生们...
- Come on, sit down. Sit down. - What's he so wise about? I'm telling ya...
- 坐下吧，请坐 - 他有什么好得意的？我告诉你们...
Come on. Now we're not gonna get anywhere fighting.
算了吧，我们不是来吵架的
- Whose turn is it next? - Oh, his. Number five.
- 接下来到谁了？ - 哦，到他了，五号
May I... Can I pass?
我可以... 我可以弃权吗？
Well... That's your privilege.
嗯... 那是你的权利
How about the next gentleman?
下一位先生呢？
Oh. Well... I don't know.
哦，嗯...我不知道
I started to be convinced, you know, very early in the case.
打从一开始 我就相信他有罪
You see, I was looking for a motive.
你瞧，我一直在寻找他的犯罪动机
That's very important because if you don't have a motive, where's your case, right?
这是很重要的。因为没有犯罪动机 案子就无法成立，对吧？
Anyway, that testimony from those people across the hall from the kid's apartment,
总之，住在孩子家公寓的人 在法庭做出的证词...
that was very powerful. Didn't they say something about a fight, an argument,
非常有利 他们提到死者曾和他儿子...
between the old man and his son around about seven o'clock that night?
在当晚七点左右打斗或者争吵
- I could be wrong but... - It was eight o'clock, not seven.
- 也许我记错了，是... - 是八点钟，不是七点
They heard an argument. Then they heard the father hit the boy twice.
他们听到了争吵 听到死者打了他儿子两下
Finally they saw the boy run, angry, out of the house. What does that prove?
最后他们看到那孩子愤怒地冲出家门 那能证明什么呢？
It don't prove anything. It's just part of the picture.
不能证明什么 那是事实的一部分
You said it provided a motive. So did the prosecution.
你认为那反映了杀人动机 公检方也那么认为
That wasn't a very strong motive.
但我觉得那样的动机还不够强烈
This boy has been hit so many times that violence is practically...
这孩子常常被打 暴力对他来说...
It's a normal state of affairs with him.
早就是司空见惯的事
I just can't see two slaps in the face provoking him into committing murder.
我不觉得脸上挨两巴掌 就足以让他气到去杀人
It may have been two too many. Everyone has a breaking point.
或许他被逼到受不了了 每个人都有极限
Anything else?
还有其他要说的吗？
- No. - OK. How about you?
- 没了 - 好，你呢？
I don't know. It's all been said.
我不知道，话都被他们说完了
You can talk here for ever. It's still the same thing.
我们可以一直耗下去 结论还是一样
This kid is five for 0. Well, look at his record.
看看他的记录 这孩子没干过好事
When he was 10, he was in children's court: He threw a rock at a teacher.
他10岁就上了少年法庭： 朝老师扔石头
When he was 15, he was in reform school: He stole a car.
15岁进了感化院： 他偷了一部车
He's been arrested for muggin'. He was picked up twice for knife fightin'.
他曾因抢劫被捕 还曾因持刀械斗被抓过两回
They say he's real handy with a knife. Oh, this is a very fine boy.
他们说他的确是个用刀高手 他可真是个「好孩子」
Ever since he was five, his father beat him up regularly. He used his fists.
从5岁开始 他父亲就常常对他拳打脚踢
So would I. A kid like that?
有那种孩子我也会那么做
It's these kids - the way they are nowadays.
现在的孩子 都是那个样子
When I was a kid, I used to call my father "sir".
我小时候 都会叫我爸爸「父亲大人」
That's right. Ever hear a kid call his father that any more?
对吧 现在哪个孩子还会那样喊？
Fathers don't seem to think it's important any more.
现在的父亲也不认为这很重要
- You got any kids? - Three.
- 你有孩子吗？ - 我有三个小孩
I got one.
我有一个儿子
He's 22 years old.
今年22岁了
When he was nine years old, he ran away from a fight.
他9岁大时 从一场打斗中逃跑了
I saw it. I was so embarrassed, I almost threw up.
我目睹那一幕觉得丢脸到家了 差点没吐出来
I said "I'm gonna make a man out of you if I have to break you in two tryin'."
我说「就算磨掉你的小命 也要让你变成一个男子汉」
Well, I made a man out of him.
好吧，我终于让他变成男子汉了
When he was 16, we had a fight.
他16岁时我们打了一架
Hit me in the jaw. He was a big kid.
他打中了我的下巴 我儿子非常高大
I haven't seen him for two years.
我已经两年没看到他了
Kids.
现在的孩子...
You work your heart out...
总让父母伤透了心...
- Well, let's get goin'. - I think we're missing the point.
- 好了，让我们继续吧 - 我想我们跑题了
This boy's the product of a broken home and a filthy neighbourhood.
这孩子来自破碎家庭 住在贫民窟
We can't help that. We're here to decide his innocence or guilt,
对此我们爱莫能助 我们在这儿是要判决他是否有罪
not to go into the reasons why he grew up the way he did.
而不是讨论他悲惨一生的原因
He was born in a slum. Slums are breeding grounds for criminals.
他生在贫民窟 那是犯罪的温床
It's no secret that children from slums are potential menaces to society. I think...
那可不是秘密，来自贫民窟的孩子 出了社会八成会变成恶棍。我想...
You can say that again. The kids who crawl out of these places are real trash.
说得好 来自那种地方的孩子都是垃圾
- I don't want any part of them. - Listen, I... I've lived in a slum all my life.
- 我可不想跟他们被归为同一类 - 听着，我...我一直都住在贫民窟里
- Wait a minute. - Please. I...
- 等一下 - 让我说完，拜托，我...
I've played in back yards that were filled with garbage.
小时候 我在塞满垃圾的后院玩耍
- Maybe you can still smell it on me. - Listen, sonny...
- 也许你现在还可以在我身上闻到垃圾味 - 听我说...
Come on, now. There's nothing personal.
- 别那样，这件事无关私人恩怨 - 他的话很关私人恩怨
Come on, fella. He didn't mean you. Let's not be so sensitive.
别这样，伙计。他并不是针对你 让我们不要那么敏感
This sensitivity I can understand.
我能了解这种「敏感」
OK, look. Let's stop the arguing. We're only wasting time.
好了，大家别吵了 我们只是在浪费时间
Your turn down there. Let's go.
现在轮到你了 让我们继续吧
I didn't expect a turn. I thought you were all gonna to try to convince me.
没想到还有我发言的机会 我以为你们想轮流说服我呢
- That was the idea. - I forgot. He's right.
- 那不是你们之前的打算么 - 我给忘了，他说的对
He's the one keeping us in here. Let's hear what he's got to say.
是他害我们被困在这儿的 让我们听听他的说法吧
Wait. We decided to do this a certain way. I think we ought to stick to it.
等一下。既然我们说好轮流说服他了 我想我们应该坚持下去
Oh, stop being a kid, will ya?
哦，别孩子气了，成不？
- What do you mean, a kid? - What do you think I mean? K-I-D: Kid.
- 你什么意思？「孩子气」？ - 听不懂吗？孩-子-气
Just because I'm trying to keep this organised?
什么事儿，就因为 我想让一切有条不紊？
Here, you take on the responsibility. I'll just keep my mouth shut.
给，交给你了 我愿意把嘴闭上
- Why are you gettin' so hot? Calm down. - Don't tell me to calm down.
- 你为什么要那么生气？冷静点 - 别叫我冷静
You want to take the chair? Take the chair.
你想主持会议吧？ 快来亲自主持
Did you ever see such a thing?
你们见过这种事吗？
- You think it's funny? - Forget it, fella. It's unimportant.
- 听着，你觉得这很可笑吗？ - 算了吧，伙计，整件事都不重要
Unimportant? Here, you try it.
不重要？你来试试看
Nobody wants to change. You're doing a beautiful job.
不，没有人想改变现状 你做得非常好
Yeah, you're doin' great. Just great, fella. You stay in there and pitch.
是的，你做得很好，伙计 你仍然是会议的主持人
All right, let's hear from somebody.
好吧，我们来听听某人的说法
Well, if you want me to tell you how I feel about it, it's all right with me.
好的，如果你们要我说出我的感受 我一点都不介意
- Boy, I don't care what you do. - All right. I don't have anything brilliant.
- 老天，我才不在乎你怎么想的 - 没错，我不比你们任何一人更聪明
I only know as much as you do.
我跟你们知道的一样多
According to the testimony, the boy looks guilty. Maybe he is.
根据证词，那孩子看起来有罪 也许他确实有罪
I sat there in court for six days listening while the evidence built up.
六天来我坐在法庭上 听到目击者接连不断提出证据
Everybody sounded so positive.
大家的语气都异常肯定
I began to get a peculiar feeling about this trial. I mean, nothing is that positive.
于是我对这次审判产生了特别的感觉 我的意思是，没有什么事能那么绝对
There are questions I'd have liked to ask. Maybe they wouldn't mean anything but...
我想提出一些问题 也许它们毫无意义，但是...
I felt that the defence wasn't conducting a thorough enough cross-examination.
我觉得被告并没有 被全面的交叉讯问过
He let too many things go by-little things.
他遗漏了太多的细节 一些小细节
What little things? When they don't ask questions,
什么小细节？ 听着，律师不提出问题...
it's because they know the answers already.
是因为他们早知道答案了
It's also possible for a lawyer to be just plain stupid, isn't it? I mean, it's possible.
也可能律师是个大笨蛋吧？ 我是说，这也是有可能的
You sound like you met my brother-in-law once.
听起来你已经 见过我大舅子了
I kept putting myself in the kid's place. I'd have asked for another lawyer, I think.
我试着让自己站在孩子的角度来想 我会去请另一位律师继续帮我辩护
I mean, if I was on trial for my life,
我的意思是 如果这场判决攸关我的生死
I'd want my lawyer to tear the prosecution witnesses to shreds, or at least try to.
我会希望我的律师反驳 目击者的证词，至少试试也好
Look, there was one alleged eyewitness to this killing.
注意 这个案件有一个目击证人
Someone else claims he heard the killing, saw the boy run out after,
还有一人听到了凶杀 事后还看到那孩子冲出屋外...
and there was circumstantial evidence.
同时还出现了 一些间接证据
But those two witnesses were the entire case for the prosecution.
但是那两个证人 才是本案的关键
Supposing they're wrong?
假如他们俩都错了呢？
What do you mean? What's the point of having witnesses at all?
你这是什么意思？ 那他们还叫目击证人吗？
- Could they be wrong? - Those people were under oath.
- 他们有可能错吗？ - 你想说什么，他们在法庭可都发过誓的
They're only people. People make mistakes. Could they be wrong?
他们只是人，是人就可能犯错 他们有可能犯错吗？
- Well, no. I don't think so. - Do you know so?
- 不，我觉得不会 - 那么，你肯定他们没错吗？
Nobody can know a thing like that. This isn't an exact science.
没有人知道他们对错 这又不是在做科学论证
That's right, it isn't.
说得对，这不是
OK, let's get to the point.
好了，让我们谈谈正事
What about the switch knife they found in the old man's chest?
插在死者胸口的折叠刀 又是怎么回事？
Some people haven't talked yet. Shouldn't we go in order?
等一下，有人还没发言 我们不是该照顺序发言吗？
They'll get a chance to talk. Be quiet a second, will ya?
有他们的机会 尽管安静点儿，好吗？
What about the knife this fine, upright boy admitted buying the night of the killing?
这把刀是怎么回事？这个「善良正直」的孩子 承认案发当晚买了这把刀
- Let's talk about it. - All right. Let's get it in here and look at it.
- 让我们谈谈它吧 - 好啊，让我们来看看那把凶刀
- I'd like to see it again. Mr Foreman? - Why do we have to see it again?
- 我想再看看那把刀，团长先生？ - 我们为什么还要再看它？
The gentleman has a right to see exhibits in evidence.
这位先生有权要求审视物证
- Say, could you bring us the knife? - The knife? Sure.
- 我说，能不能把凶刀拿给我们？ - 那把刀？没问题
The knife and the way it was bought is strong evidence, don't you think?
凶刀及购买方式是一项强有力的证据 你不觉得是吗？
- I do. - Good. Let's take the facts one at a time.
- 我也觉得是 - 好，让我们一样一样检视所有事实
One: The boy admitted leaving the house at eight o'clock at night
一：那孩子承认在八点钟离开家里
after being slapped by his father.
因为他父亲扇了他几巴掌
No, he didn't say "slapped". He said "punched". There's a difference.
不，他没有说他被「扇巴掌」 他说他被「拳头揍」，那是不一样的
After being hit several times by his father.
因为他父亲打了他几下
Two: He went directly to a local junk shop where he bought one of those...
二：他径直跑到附近的二手店 买了其中一把...
- Switch knives. - Switchblade knives.
- 折叠刀 - 开刃的折叠刀
This wasn't an ordinary knife. It had a very unusual carved handle and blade.
这不是一把常见的刀子 刀柄和刀锋都刻有独一无二的图案
The storekeeper said it was the only one of its kind he had ever had in stock.
店主说他店里 只有唯一一把这样的刀子
Three: He met some friends of his in front of a tavern about 8.45. Am I right so far?
三：8点45分左右，他在 酒吧前遇到几位朋友，到此为止都对吧？
- Yes, you are. - You bet he is.
- 是的，你说的对 - 你可以打赌他说的没错
He talked with his friends for an hour, leaving them at 9.45.
他跟朋友一起聊了大概一小时 在9点45分左右离开
During this time, they saw the switch knife.
在这段时间里 他的朋友们看到了那把折叠刀
Four: They identified the death weapon in court as that very same knife.
四：他们在法庭上指认 凶刀和那把刀一模一样
Five: He arrived home at about ten o'clock.
五：大约10点钟他回到家里
This is where the stories offered by the State and the boy diverge slightly.
从这里开始，公诉律师和被告的说词 开始出现分歧
He claims that he went to a movie at about 11.30,
被告声称自己 在11点30分左右去看电影
returning home at 3.10 to find his father dead and himself arrested.
凌晨3点10分他回到家 发现父亲已死，自己遭到逮捕
He also claims that the two detectives threw him down a half a flight of stairs.
他还控诉 逮捕他的两名警察将他丢下楼梯
What happened to the knife? He claims it fell through a hole in his pocket
而那把折叠刀呢？ 他声称刀子从口袋破洞掉出去丢失了
on the way to the movies, sometime between 11.30 and 3.10,
就在去电影院的路上 大概11点半到3点10分之间
and that he never saw it again. Now, there is a tale, gentlemen.
之后他从没再看到过那把刀 这是一个谎言，先生
I think it's clear the boy never went to the movies that night.
我想事实非常明显 那孩子当晚根本没去看电影
No one in the house saw him go out. No one at the theatre identified him.
那栋公寓没有人看到他11点半离家 电影院也没有人能给他作证
He couldn't even remember the names of the pictures he saw.
他甚至记不住那部电影的名字
What actually happened is this.
真正的事实是
The boy stayed home, had another fight with his father,
这孩子待在家里 又跟他父亲发生了争执
stabbed him to death and left the house at 10 minutes after 12.
他刺杀了父亲 并且在12点10分离家
He even wiped the knife clean of fingerprints.
他甚至还把刀上的指纹 擦得一干二净
Are you trying to tell me that this knife fell through a hole in the boy's pocket,
难道你想告诉我说 这把刀从那孩子口袋的破洞掉出来
someone picked it up, went to the boy's house
某人捡起它 跑到这孩子家
and stabbed his father with it just to test its sharpness?
然后用它杀死那孩子的父亲 只是为了测试刀子锋利不锋利？
No, but it's possib/e the boy lost his knife
没有，我是说有可能 那孩子真的丢失了刀子
and somebody else stabbed his father with a similar knife.
而有人拿一把类似的刀子 刺死了他父亲，只是可能
Take a look at this knife.
好好看看这把刀
It's a very unusual knife.
它是一把独一无二的刀子
I've never seen one like it. Neither had the storekeeper who sold it to the boy.
我从没见过跟它一样的刀子 卖出它的店主也从没见过
Aren't you asking us to accept an incredible coincidence?
难道你想叫我们接受 根本不可能的巧合吗？
- I'm just saying a coincidence is possible. - And I say it's not possible.
- 我只是说这种巧合是有可能的 - 但是我说那绝不可能
Where did that come from?
你从哪儿弄来这玩意儿的？
- It's the same knife! - What do you think you're doin'?
- 跟那把凶刀一模一样！ - 你到底在做什么？
- Where did you get it? - I went out walking last night.
- 你从哪儿弄到它的？ - 我昨晚出去散了会儿步
Through the boy's neighbourhood.
经过那孩子住的社区
I bought that at a pawn shop two blocks from the boy's house. It cost six dollars.
我在离那孩子家两个街区的当铺买下它 只花了我六块钱
It's against the law to buy or sell switchblade knives.
买卖折叠刀是违法的
- That's right. I broke the law. - You pulled a real bright trick.
- 说得对，我犯法了 - 听着，你这招儿太绝了
Now supposing you tell me what it proves.
就算你说的对
- Maybe there are ten knives like that. - Maybe there are!
- 但也许还有10把跟这一样的刀子 - 也许是有那么多！
What does it mean? You found a knife like it. What's that? The discovery of the age?
你什么意思？你找到一把类似的刀子 那又怎么了？是了不起的大发现吗？
You think somebody else did the stabbing with exactly the same kind of knife?
你得相信有人 可能拿类似的刀子杀了他父亲
- The odds are a million to one. - It's possible!
- 机率只有百万分之一 - 那也是有可能的！
- But not very probable. - OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
- 但可能性不大 - 好了，伙计们。让我们都坐下吧
There's no point standing around all over the place.
我们不必站着说话
It's interesting that he'd find a knife exactly like the boy's.
知道吗，他能找到跟凶刀一模一样的刀子 真是太有趣了
- What's interesting about it? Interesting! - I just thought it was interesting.
- 哪里有趣了？有趣个毛线！ - 我不知道，我就是觉得有趣
Eleven of us still think he's guilty.
我们11个人仍然 觉得他有罪
Right. You're not gonna change anybody's mind.
对 你不可能改变任何人的想法
If you wanna hang this jury, go ahead.
要是你想让这案子成为悬判 尽管去试吧
The kid'll be tried again and found guilty, as sure as he's born.
到头来这孩子还是被判有罪 这是毫无疑问的
You're probably right.
也许你是对的
So, what are you gonna do? We can be here all night.
那么，你打算怎么做？ 我们可以一晚上耗在这儿
It's only one night. A boy may die.
对我们来说只是耗一晚 可是对那孩子而言可能会没命
Well, why don't we just set up house here?
那么 我们干脆在这里扎营好了？
Someone send for a pinochle deck
找个人支起一张棋牌桌
and we'll just sweat the whole thing out right here.
我们就可以在这儿 度过美好的一晚
- I don't think he oughta joke about it. - What do you want me to do about it?
- 我觉得他不该拿这件事开玩笑 - 那你想让我怎么办？
I don't see what the knife has got to do with anything.
哦，我看不出这把刀 跟这案子有任何关系
Somebody saw the kid stab his father. What more do we need?
有人看到这孩子杀了自己的父亲 你还想要什么证据？
You guys can talk the ears right off my head.
我听够你们的废话了 懂不懂？
I got three garages going to pot. So let's get done and get outta here.
我还要跑三家修车厂 赶快决定下来然后离开这儿吧！
The knife was important to the district attorney. He spent a day...
对检察官而言，那把刀子非常重要 他花了足足一天时间...
He's a 15th assistant or something. What does he know?
他只是个十五流的小角色 他懂什么
Let's hold it down. These side arguments are only slowin' us up.
让我们就此打住吧 这些争吵只会拖慢事情进展
- Well, what about it? - You're the only one.
- 好吧，怎么办呢？ - 只有你跟大家不一样
I have a proposition to make to all of you. I'm going to call for another vote.
我要向你们大家提出一项建议 我们何不再投一次票
I want you eleven men to...
我要求你们11个人...
vote by secret written ballot.
以书面方式来秘密投票
I'll abstain. If there are eleven votes for guilty, I won't stand alone.
我弃权。如果有11张票是「有罪」 我就不再反对你们
We'll take in a guilty verdict to the judge right now.
我们可以立刻向法官 提出「有罪」的判决
But if anyone votes not guilty, we'll stay here and talk it out.
但是只要有一张票是「无罪」 我们就得待在这儿，把事情彻底弄清楚
- That's it. If you want to try it, I'm ready. - All right. Let's do it the hard way.
- 就这样。如果你们愿意，我准备好了 - 好吧，让我们再度受苦吧
That sounds fair. Everyone agreed? Anyone doesn't agree?
听起来很公平，大家都同意吗？ 有人反对吗？
OK, pass these along.
好的，请帮忙传下去
Guilty.
「有罪」
Not guilty.
「无罪」
- Boy, how do you like that? - And another chap flips his wings!
- 天啊，怎么会这样？ - 又有一个坏蛋在搞破坏！
All right. Who was it? Come on, I wanna know.
好吧，谁干的？ 快点，我想知道
Excuse me. This was a secret ballot. We all agreed on that, no?
对不起，这是秘密投票 我们都同意这一点，不是吗？
If the gentleman wants it to remain secret...
如果这位先生不想被公开...
Secret? What do you mean? There are no secrets in a jury room. I know who it was.
秘密？你什么意思？ 陪审团里没有秘密！我知道是谁干的
Brother, you really are somethin'. You vote guilty like the rest of us,
老兄，你可真行 你跟我们其他人一样投了「有罪」
then some golden-voiced preacher tears your heart out -
然后某些家伙的胡言乱语说动了你...
some underprivileged kid couldn't help becoming a murderer -
社会地位低下的孩子不可能是杀人犯
and you change your vote. If that isn't the most sickening...
于是你改变了投票 如果这还不够恶心的话...
Why don't you drop a quarter in his collection box?
你为什么不丢些铜板 到他的破碗里去？
Oh, now just wait a... Listen, you can't talk to me like that. Who do you think you are?
哦，等一下...听着，你不能那样跟我说话 你以为自己是什么东西？
Calm down, calm down. It doesn't matter.
冷静，冷静。不要紧
- He's very excitable. Sit down. - Excitable? You bet I'm excitable!
- 他很容易激动。快坐下 - 激动？你最好相信我很激动！
We're tryin' to put a guilty man in the chair, where he belongs.
我们正要把一个罪有应得的家伙 送上电椅
Someone starts tellin' us fairy tales and we're listenin'!
一些人开始给我们讲神话故事 然后我们就相信了
- What made you change your vote? - He didn't change his vote. I did.
- 你为什么要改变主意？ - 他没有改变主意，是我
- Oh, fine. - I knew it.
- 天啊，好极了 - 我就知道
- Would you like me to tell you why? - No, I wouldn't like you to tell me why.
- 想让我告诉你为什么吗？ - 不，我可不想听
- I'd like to anyway, if you don't mind. - Do we have to listen to this?
- 无论如何我都要说，如果你不介意 - 我们非得听这些废话不可吗？
- The man wants to talk. - Thank you.
- 有话请讲 - 谢谢你
This gentleman has been standing alone against us.
这位先生一直孤军奋战 跟我们对抗
He doesn't say the boy is not guilty.
他并没有说这孩子「无罪」
He just isn't sure. It's not easy to stand alone against the ridicule of others.
他只是说他无法确定「有罪」 要独自对抗他人的荒谬言论，并不容易
So he gambled for support and I gave it to him. I respect his motives.
所以他孤注一掷争取支持 于是我就支持他了。因为我赞同他的动机
The boy on trial is probably guilty, but... I want to hear more.
根据受审结果，这孩子看样子的确犯罪了 但是...我希望听到更多证词
The vote is ten to two. I'm talking! You have no right to leave this room!
现在票数是10比2。我正在发言！ 你没有权利离开这儿！
He can't hear you. He never will. Let's sit down.
他不会听你的，死都不会听 我们坐下吧
- Shall we continue? - Well, I think we ought to take a break.
- 我们可以继续了吗？ - 我想我们应该休息一下
You know, one man's inside and I think we ought to wait for him.
你知道，有人进了洗手间 我们应该等他
Looks like we're really hung up here, huh?
看样子我们还真的 被困在这儿了，对吧？
I mean, that thing with the old man, that was pretty unexpected.
我是说，这老头做的事 真是大大出乎意料
Wish I could figure out some way we could break it up.
真希望我能想办法 突破这个困局
You know, in advertising... I told you I worked in an agency?
知道吗，在广告界... 我提过我在广告公司上班吗？
Some pretty strange people work there. Well, not strange, really.
那里聚集了一帮怪人 当然了，其实也不是怪人
I guess it's just they have peculiar ways of expressing themselves.
我想那只是他们 表达自己的方式很特别
I suppose it's the same in your business too, huh?
我猜在你那一行 也是一样的吧？
- What do you do? - I'm a watchmaker.
- 你是做什么的？ - 我是个钟表匠
Really? I imagine the finest watchmakers in the world come from Europe.
真的吗？我以为 最好的钟表匠都来自欧洲
Anyway, in an agency, when we reach a point like this...
总之，在广告公司里 要是遇到这种情形...
I'm telling him, in an ad agency when a point like this is reached in a meeting,
我正告诉他，在广告公司 要是开会时候遇到这种情形
there's always some character ready with an idea, see.
总会有人想出好点子来 瞧
It kills me. It's the weirdest thing,
真能把我给笑死 非常奇怪的...
the way they sometimes precede their idea with a phrase.
他们总是用一句话 来说出自己的心声
Like, some account exec will get up and he'll say:
比如 有个业务员站起来说
"OK, here's an idea. Let's... run it up the flagpole and see if anyone salutes it."
「好，我想到一个点子，我们把它升上旗杆 看看会不会有人向它敬礼」
I mean, it's idiotic, but it's funny.
我是说，虽然挺蠢的 但真的非常好笑
I... got a little excited back there.
我... 刚才有点太激动了
I... didn't mean to get nasty.
无意要为难大家
Glad you're not one of those who lets these emotional appeals influence him.
还好你不是那种 会被他人情绪影响的人
I don't know what's the matter with that fan.
我真不知道 那个电扇到底怎么了
- Are you a salesman? - I'm an architect.
- 你是推销员吗？ - 我是建筑师
You know what the soft sell is?
你知道「软性推销」吗？
Well, you've got it, believe me.
说真的，你有这个本事 相信我
I've got a different technique.
我用的技巧跟别人不一样
Laughs, drinks, jokes, tricks. You know?
微笑、陪客人喝几杯 说说笑话、耍耍小把戏，你懂吧？
Yeah.
没错
Hit 'em where they live-that's my motto.
抓住他们生活的脉动 那就是我的座右铭
I made 27 grand last year sellin' marmalade.
去年我卖橘皮果酱 赚了两万七
That's not bad. I mean, you know, considerin' marmalade.
成绩不坏，我是说，你知道吗 那可是橘皮果酱
What are you gettin' out of this? Kicks?
待在这里能得到什么好处？ 刺激吗？
Or did somebody bump you on the head once and you haven't gotten over it?
还是有人曾经撞到你的头 你到现在还耿耿于怀？
- Maybe. - You know, you do-gooders are all alike.
- 也许吧 - 知道吗，你们全都是不切实际的家伙
You're always blowin' your stacks over some guy that fanned.
你们老是把自己的快乐 建立在别人的痛苦上
But what are you wastin' our time for?
但是 你浪费我们的时间有什么用？
Why don't you donate five dollars to the cause? Maybe it'll make you feel better.
干脆给这个案子捐上5美元 也许能让你觉得舒服点
This kid is guilty, pal.
这孩子确实犯罪了 伙计
It's as plain as the nose on your face. So why don't we stop wastin' our time here?
一清二楚 所以干嘛不停止浪费大伙的时间呢？
We're gonna all get sore throats if we keep it up.
再吵下去 大家喉咙都要痛了
What difference does it make if you get it here or at the ball game?
你在这儿或是去看球赛 又有什么差别呢？
No difference, pal.
没差别，伙计
No difference at all.
完全没差别
- Nice bunch of guys, huh? - They're about the same as anyone else.
- 挺不错的一伙人，是吧？ - 他们跟其他人一样
Boy, what a murderous day.
天啊 真是够惨的一天
- Do you think we'll be much longer? - I don't know.
- 你觉得我们还会继续很久吗？ - 我不知道
He's guilty for sure. Not a doubt in the whole world.
他绝对有罪 全世界没一个人会怀疑
We should've... We should've been done already.
我们早该... 我们早该做出判决
Oh, I don't mind, you know.
哦，我并不介意 知道吗
Beats workin'.
比上班好玩多了
- You think he's not guilty, huh? - I don't know. It's possible.
- 你觉得他无罪，是吧？ - 我不知道，只是可能
Well, I don't know you, but I'm bettin' you've never been wronger in your life.
好吧，我不了解你 但是我打赌你从未犯过错
You're wastin' your time. You ought to wrap it up.
你在浪费自己的时间 你该收拾东西结束了
Supposing you were the one who was on trial?
假设接受审判的人 是你自己呢？
Well, I'm not used to supposin'. I'm just a workin' man.
这个，我不常做假设 我只是个上班族
My boss does the supposin'. But...
要动脑筋的是我的老板 但是...
I'll try one.
让我试试看
Supposin' you talk us all out of this and...
假设你真的 说服了我们每一个人...
the kid really did knife his father, huh?
但这孩子真的拿刀 杀了他父亲呢？
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Sorry, blue eyes.
真遗憾 大帅哥
- Well, where else? - OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
好了，小伙子们 让我们都坐下
- Looks like we'll be here for dinner. - OK, now let's get down to business.
- 看来我们得在这儿吃晚饭了 - 好，现在让我们来谈正事
- Who wants to start? - I will.
- 谁想发言？ - 我有话要说
- OK, go. - You, down there.
- 好，请讲 - 你，那边那位
The old man who lived downstairs says he heard the kid yell "I'm gonna kill ya."
住在案发现场楼下的老人 说他听到那孩子大叫说「我要杀了你」
A second later, he heard the body hit the floor.
一秒钟后 他听到有人摔倒的声音
He ran to the door and saw the kid run out of the house. What's that mean to you?
他跑到门口，看到那孩子逃离了房子 你有什么看法？
I wonder how clearly he heard the boy's voice through the ceiling.
我在想，那孩子的声音隔着天花板 他能听得多清楚呢？
He didn't. The window was open. So was the one upstairs. It was a hot night.
他并非透过天花板。他的窗户是开着的 案发现场的窗户也是开着的，那天晚上很热
It was another apartment. It's not easy to identify a shouting voice.
但是并不是同一个房间 要在另一间房内辨识一声喊叫，并不容易
He identified it in court.
他在法庭上已经指证了
The lady across the street looked right in the open window and saw the stabbing.
街对面的女士从开着的窗户 也看到了行凶过程
- Isn't that enough for you? - No, it isn't.
- 难道对你来说这些还不够吗？ - 不，的确是不够
Boy, how do you like this guy? It's like talkin' into a dead phone.
天啊，你们觉得这家伙怎么样？ 这简直是对牛弹琴
She said she saw it through the windows of a moving el train.
她说她透过移动的电车窗 看到了案发经过
There were six cars on the train. She saw it through the last two.
电车一共6节车厢 她是透过最后两节车厢看到的
She remembered insignificant details. How can you argue with that?
她的确记得住小细节 我看不出你还有什么可质疑的？
Has anybody here any idea how long it would take an el...
在座的各位，有谁曾经想过 电车要花多长时间...
This isn't a game.
这不是在玩游戏！
Did you see him?
你们看到了吗？
The nerve! The absolute nerve!
神经病！ 彻头彻尾的神经病！
- Forget it. It's not important. - This isn't a game?
- 算了吧，没什么 - 这不就是在玩游戏吗？
- Who does he think he is? - Forget it now.
- 他以为他是什么东西？ - 算了吧
Any idea how long it takes an el train at medium speed to pass a given point?
你们曾经想过，电车以平均速度运行 要花费多长时间才能通过某一点吗？
- What has that to do with it? - Guess.
- 这有什么意义？ - 多长时间，猜猜？
- I wouldn't have any idea. - What do you think?
- 我从不妄加揣测 - 你觉得呢？
- I don't know. Ten, twelve seconds? - A pretty good guess. Anyone else?
- 我不知道。10、或者12秒？ - 猜得好。其他人呢？
- Sounds right to me. - What's the guessing game for?
- 听着挺合理 - 少来了，这个猜谜游戏有什么意义？
- What do you say? - Ten seconds.
- 你觉得呢？ - 10秒钟差不多
- All right. What are you getting at? - This.
- 好吧，就算10秒钟，你想说什么？ - 是这样...
It takes a six-car el train ten seconds to pass a given point.
一辆6节车厢的电车 要花费10秒钟才能通过某一点
Say the given point is the open window of the room where the killing took place.
我们说这一点正是 发生凶案的那个窗口
You can reach out and almost touch the el tracks, right?
在那里几乎一伸手 就可以摸到电车铁轨，对吧？
Now let me ask you this. Has anyone here ever lived near the el tracks?
现在我要问你们一个问题 你们之中有人曾住在铁轨旁吗？
I just finished painting an apartment that overlooked an el line. It took three days.
我刚漆完一间可以俯瞰电车铁轨的公寓 一共花了3天时间
- What was it like? Noisy? - Oh, brother! No matter. We were punchy.
- 感觉怎么样？很吵吗？ - 天啊，吵死了。不过无所谓，本来大家都昏沉沉的
I lived in an apartment near the el line once.
我曾在电车铁轨旁 一栋公寓住过
When the window's open, the train noise is almost unbearable.
当窗户打开时 电车经过的噪音几乎无法忍受
- You can hardly hear yourself think. - Will you get to the point?
- 甚至吵得你无法思考 - 请你说重点
I will. Now, let's take two pieces of testimony and try to put them together.
我会的 现在，让我们把两个人的证词拼在一起
First: The old man in the apartment downstairs.
第一：公寓楼下的那位老人
He says he heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you",
他说他听到那孩子说 「我要杀了你」
and a split second later heard a body hit the floor.
一秒钟后他听到 有人摔倒的声音
- One second later. - Right.
- 一秒钟后 - 对
Second: The woman across the street
第二：街对面那位女士
swore positively she looked out of the window and saw the killing
她发誓说她向窗户看时 透过一辆移动电车的最后两节车厢...
through the last two cars of a passing el train-the last two cars.
...看到了案发经过 对吧，最后两节车厢
- What are you givin' us here? - Now, just a minute.
- 你到底想说什么 - 稍等
We've agreed that it takes ten seconds for a train to pass a given point.
我们都同意，电车得花费10秒钟 才能完全通过某一点
Since the woman saw the killing through the last two cars,
由于这位女士是通过 最后两节车厢看到案发的
we can assume that the body hit the floor just as the train went by.
我们可以因此假定死者 正是在电车经过时摔倒在地的
Therefore, the train had been roaring by the old man's window
因此，电车已经开始 轰隆隆经过老人的窗前了
a full ten seconds before the body hit the floor.
在死者摔倒前 足足开了十秒钟
The old man - "I'm gonna kill you", body hitting the floor a second later -
这位老人——「我要杀了你」 ——一秒钟后有人摔倒
would have had to hear the boy's words with the el roaring past his nose!
他得在近在咫尺的电车 轰鸣而过的同时，听到那孩子的声音！
- It's not possible he heard it. - Of course he heard it.
- 他不可能听得到 - 他当然能听到
- Do you think so? - He said he yelled at the top of his voice.
- 你觉得能吗？ - 他说那孩子是扯着喉咙大喊的
He couldn't have identified the voice with the el roaring by.
当时电车正轰鸣而过 他不可能分辨出声音是那孩子的
It was a matter of seconds! Nobody can be that accurate.
这是几秒钟的事！ 谁能测量的那么准确！
Testimony that could put a boy into the electric chair shou/d be that accurate.
我觉得要送那孩子上电椅的证词 必须得那么准确才行
- I don't think he could have heard it. - Maybe he didn't, with all that el noise.
- 我不信他能听得清 - 也许那么吵，他真听不清楚
- What are you people talkin' about? - It stands to reason he couldn't have.
- 你们胡说什么？ - 有理由相信他确实听不清
- Why lie? What's he got to gain? - Attention, maybe.
- 他为什么要撒谎？对他有什么好处？ - 也许，他想引起别人注意
You keep comin' in with bright sayings. Send 'em to a paper! They pay $3 apiece!
你既然想出这么多理论 把它们卖到报社吧，一份稿费3块钱！
What are you talkin' to him like that for?
你为什么要那样对他说话？
A guy who talks like that to an old man really oughta get stepped on.
那样跟老人说话的人 应该受到谴责，知道吗？
You oughta have more respect, mister.
你得学着去尊重别人，先生
You say stuff like that to him again... I'm gonna lay you out.
你再敢那样跟他说话... 我一定给你好看
You go ahead. You say anything you like.
你可以继续了 你想说什么就说吧
Why do you think the old man might lie?
为什么你觉得 那位老人要撒谎呢？
It was just that I looked at him for a very long time.
在法庭上 我一直盯着他看
The seam of his jacket was split, under the shoulder.
他穿的外套看起来裂开了 就在肩膀下面
Did you notice that? I mean, to come into court like that.
你们注意到了吗？ 我是说他上法庭还穿成那样
He was a very old man in a torn jacket.
他是个穿着破外套的老头子
And he walked very slowly to the stand.
他走上证人席时 步伐非常缓慢
He was dragging his left leg and trying to hide it,
他的左脚一瘸一拐的 却努力想要掩饰它
because he was ashamed.
因为他觉得自己很丢脸
I think I know this man better than anyone here.
我认为我比你们任何一个人 都更了解那个老头子
This is a quiet, frightened,
他是个安静、怯懦
insignificant old man who...
不起眼的老头子...
who has been nothing all his life.
一辈子无所成就
Who has never had recognition or his name in the newspapers.
没有人认得他 他的名字也从没上过报纸
Nobody knows him. Nobody quotes him.
没有人知道他 也不会听他说话
Nobody seeks his advice after 75 years.
75年来 从没有人向他征询过意见
Gentlemen, that's a very sad thing - to mean nothing.
先生们，默默无闻 是一件令人伤感的事
A man like this needs to be quoted, to be listened to.
向他那样的人，希望别人去征询他的意见 希望有人倾听他说话
To be quoted just once - very important to him.
即使只征询他一次 对他来说都非常重要
It would be so hard for him to recede into the background.
要他放弃这个机会 真的很难
Wait a minute. Are you tellin' us he'd lie just so he could be important once?
等一下。你的意思是他说谎 只是为了体验当大人物的滋味？
No. He wouldn't really lie.
不 事实上他不算是说谎
But perhaps he made himself believe he heard those words
或许他幻想自己 真的听到了那些话
and recognised the boy's face.
并且认出了那孩子的脸
That's the most fantastic story ever.
没有比这更棒的故事了
How can you make up a thing like that? What do you know about it?
你是如何编出这样的故事的？ 你又知道多少呢？
- Does anybody want a cough drop? - I'll take one.
- 谁想吃喉糖？ - 给我一颗吧
I still don't see how anybody can think he's not guilty.
我还是不明白 你们为什么认为他无罪？
There's something else I'd like to talk about for a minute. Thanks.
还有一件事 我想跟你们讨论一下。谢谢
We've proved the old man couldn't have heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you."
我们已经证实那位老人 听不到那孩子说「我要杀了你」
- You didn't prove it at all! - Wait. Supposing he really did hear it?
- 你根本没有证明它 - 等一下。就算他真的听到这句话了
This phrase, how many times have all of us used it? Probably thousands.
这句话咱们有多常说呢？ 恐怕上千次吧
"I could kill you for that." "Junior, do that again and I'll kill you." "Rocky, kill him."
「我要为此杀了你」、「朱尼尔，下次我非杀了你」 「洛基，快杀了他」
- It doesn't mean we'd really kill anybody. - The phrase was: "I'm gonna kill you."
- 这不代表我们真的要杀谁 - 等一下，你想说什么？这句话是「我想要杀了你」
The kid yelled it at the top of his lungs.
这个孩子用尽力气喊出来
Don't tell me he didn't mean it. Anybody says it like that, they mean it!
别告诉我他不是这个意思 任何人那样喊，都是这个意思
Gee, I don't know.
天啊 那我就不懂了
I was arguing with the guy I work next to at the bank a few weeks ago.
几个星期前 我在银行跟一位工作伙伴发生争吵
He called me an idiot, so I yelled at him.
他骂我是白痴 于是我就冲他喊那句话了
This guy is trying to make you believe what isn't so!
这家伙要你们相信 违背常理的事
The kid said he'd kill him and he did!
这孩子说要杀他 而且就真的动手了
Do you really think the boy'd shout it out so the whole neighbourhood could hear?
你觉得如果那孩子真的想杀人 会嚷嚷得让所有邻居都知道吗？
- He's much too bright for that. - Bright? He's a common, ignorant slob.
- 那他可太聪明了 - 聪明？他只是个粗俗、愚昧的小混混
He don't even speak good English.
他甚至连英语都说不（don't）好
He doesn't even speak good English.
他甚至连英语都说不（doesn't）好
Mr Foreman, I'd like to change my vote to not guilty.
团长先生，我要改变投票 我投「无罪」
- You what? - You heard me.
- 你说什么？ - 你听到了
- Are you sure? - Yeah, I'm sure.
- 你确定？ - 对，我非常确定
The vote is nine to three in favour of guilty.
投票是9比3 有罪一方占优势
Well, if this isn't the livin' end!
好吧，这还不是最终结论吧！
What are you basin' it on? Stories this guy made up?
你们凭什么相信？ 就凭这家伙编的故事？
You oughta write for one of those kooky detective magazines, make a fortune.
你应该去写那些疯狂的侦探小说 准能大赚一票
For cryin' out loud, the kid's own lawyer knew he didn't stand a chance.
不是我说的，连那孩子的律师都清楚 他根本没有胜诉的机会
Right from the beginning, his own lawyer knew, and you could see it.
从一开始，他的律师就清楚 你应该知道
Boy, oh boy, I'm telling ya. This guy here is really somethin'.
天啊，我告诉你们 这个家伙真的很厉害
The kid had a lawyer, didn't he? He presented his case, not you.
那孩子请律师了，对吧？ 由那律师代理案子，不是你
- How come you say so much? - Lawyers aren't infallible.
- 你哪儿来那么多话？ - 律师并不总是绝对可靠的
- Baltimore, please. - He was court-appointed.
- 拜托，「巴尔的摩」先生 - 他可是法庭指派的律师
- What's that supposed to mean? - A lot.
- 那又怎么了？ - 那说明很多问题
He didn't want the case or he resented being appointed.
他并不想出庭打这场官司 或者他是被硬性指派的
It's the kind of case that brings no money, no glory, not much chance of winning.
这种案子赚不到钱、得不到名声 连胜诉的机会都微乎其微
That's not a very promising situation for a young lawyer.
对年轻的律师来说 这可不是个有前途的好案子
He'd really have to believe in his client to put up a good case. Obviously he didn't.
他必须得相信他的客户，才能打好官司 显然他没有相信
Of course he didn't.
他当然不信
Who the heck could?
谁他娘的会？
Except maybe some guy's mother or somebody.
或许某人的妈妈 或是某个人...
Oh, look. Will you look at the time? Come on.
听着，瞧 看看时间好吗？快点吧
Pardon me. I have made some notes here,
抱歉 我在这儿做了一些笔记...
and I would like, please, to say something.
并且有些事情想说
I have been listening very carefully and...
我一直在非常仔细地听...
it seems to me that this man has some very good points to make.
看起来这位先生 提出了一些非常好的观点
From what was presented at the trial, the boy looks guilty, on the surface.
顺着法庭证词看 这孩子从表面上看似乎有罪
- But maybe if we go deeper... - Come on, will ya?
- 但如果我们深入进去... - 少来了
There is a question I would like to ask.
我想问个问题
Let us assume that the boy really did commit the murder.
让我们假定 这孩子真的杀了人
Now, this happened at 10 minutes after 12.
案发时刻是12点10分
Now, how was he caught by the police?
那么 他是如何被警方逮捕的呢？
He came back home... at three o'clock or so,
他在夜里3点左右回到家
and he was captured by two detectives in the hallway of his house.
在家里的走廊上 被两名警察逮捕
Now, my question is: If he really had killed his father,
现在，我的问题是： 如果他真的杀了他父亲
why would he come back home three hours later?
为什么他会在3小时后回家呢？
Wouldn't he be afraid of being caught?
难道他不怕被逮到吗？
He came home for his knife. It's not nice to leave knives in people's chests.
他是回来拿刀子的 让刀子留在一个死者的胸口可不明智
Yeah, especially relatives'.
对 特别是死者还是他老爸
I don't see anything funny about it.
我一点都不觉得好笑
The boy knew the knife could be identified.
这孩子知道 有人会认出这是他的刀子
- He had to get it before the police did. - If he knew the knife could be identified,
- 他得抢在警察前面拿走刀子 - 如果他知道刀子会被认出来...
why did he leave it there in the first place?
为什么他还要把它留在现场呢？
I think we can assume the boy ran out in a state of panic, having just killed his father.
我想我们可以假设那孩子是慌张离开现场的 因为他刚杀了自己父亲
He calmed down and realised he'd left his knife there.
他冷静下来后 才意识到刀子留在现场了
This, then, depends on your definition of panic.
那么，这，就取决于 你对慌张的定义了
He would have had to be calm enough to wipe off any fingerprints left on the knife.
他必须得足够冷静 才会把刀子的指纹全部擦干净
Now, where did this panic start and where did it end?
那么，他是什么时候慌张 又是什么时候冷静呢？
You voted guilty. What side are you on?
你投了「有罪」 你到底站在哪一边？
I don't believe I have to be loyal to one side or the other.
我不觉得 我需要效忠任何一方
- I'm simply asking questions. - This is just off the top of my head but...
- 我只是提出疑问 - 这真是超出了我的理解范围，但...
If /'d done the stabbing, I'd take a chance and go back for the knife.
如果我杀了人 我会冒险取回刀子的
I'll bet he figured nobody'd seen him running out
我敢打赌那孩子以为 没人看到他逃离现场
and the body wouldn't be discovered till the next day.
而且他以为没人会发现尸体
After all, it was the middle of the night. He figured it'd be found the next day.
毕竟，那时是三更半夜 他觉得第二天才会被发现
Pardon. This is my whole point.
抱歉 这就是我的重点
The woman across the street testified that the moment after she saw the killing,
街对面的女士作证说 案发之后...
that is, a moment after the train went by,
也就是电车经过不久...
she screamed, and then went to telephone the police.
她放声尖叫 然后打电话报警
Now, the boy certainly must have heard the scream.
这时候 这孩子肯定听到了尖叫声
So he knew that somebody saw something.
所以他知道 有人看到了什么
I just don't think that he would have gone back.
我想 他是打死都不会再回家的
Two things. One: He may not have heard the scream. Perhaps it wasn't very loud.
两种可能 一：或许他没听到，因为尖叫声不大
Two: If he did, he may not have connected it with his own acts.
二：或许他听到了，但他没想到 是看到他杀人才尖叫的
He lived in a neighbourhood where screams were commonplace.
在他住的地区 尖叫声司空见惯
- There's your answer. - Maybe. Maybe the boy did kill his father.
- 这就是你要的答案 - 也许吧。也许这孩子真的杀了他父亲
Didn't hear the scream, did run out in a panic,
他没有听到尖叫声 慌张地冲出屋子
calmed down later and came back for the knife, risking being caught by the police.
3小时后冷静下来 冒着被逮捕的危险回来拿刀子
Maybe those things happened, but maybe they didn't.
也许这就是发生的事实 但也许根本不是这么回事
There's enough doubt to wonder if he was there at all at the time of the killing.
我觉得有太多疑点让我们怀疑 案发时他到底在不在场
What do you mean? Didn't the old man see him running out of the house?
你什么意思？ 那老头看到他冲出屋外了
He's twisting the facts.
他是在扭曲事实 我告诉你们
Did or didn't the old man see the kid running out of the house at 12.10?
12点10分，那老头到底 有没有看到被告冲出屋外？
- Well, did or didn't he? - He says he did.
- 说啊，到底有没有？ - 他说他看到了
Says he did? Boy, how do you like that?
说他看到了？老天，你还想怎么样？
- Witnesses can make mistakes. - Sure, when you want them to!
- 证人也会犯错的 - 对，那是你自己说的！
- Or when he wants them to! - Keep the yelling down.
- 或者是你说的！懂不懂？ - 小声一点
Maybe we need a little yelling. These guys keep going off every which way.
也许我们正需要一点喊叫 这些家伙逮住什么质疑什么
Did hear the scream, didn't hear it - what difference does it make?
听到尖叫声了吗，没听到尖叫声吗 这又有什么关系
You're talking about little details and forgetting the important stuff.
你们只会去讨论那些细枝末节 却忽略了最重要的事
- I call for another vote. - I'm talking here!
- 我提议再投一次票 - 我正发言呢！
Another vote called for.
有人要求再投一次票
Now let's take our seats.
现在请大家都坐下
I never saw so much time spent on nothin'.
我从来没见过谁 把这么多时间浪费在没意义的事上
It only takes a second.
只要一下子就好了
OK, I guess the fastest way is to find out who's voting not guilty.
好，我想最快的方法是 先表决无罪的部分
All those voting not guilty, please raise your hands.
所有投「无罪」一票的人 请举手
Still the same. One, two, three not guilty. Nine guilty.
还是一样。一、二、三票「无罪」 9票「有罪」
So now where are we? We can yakety-yak till next Tuesday. Where's it getting us?
现在我们怎么办？再这样下去，得耗到下周二 这对我们有什么好处？
Pardon. I vote not guilty.
对不起 我要投「无罪」一票
What are you talkin' about? I mean, we're all goin' crazy in here or somethin'.
你在胡说什么？ 我看，这儿的人全都疯了
The kid is guilty. Why don't you listen to the facts?
这孩子有罪 你们为什么不愿意接受事实？
Tell them, will ya? This is gettin' to be a joke.
告诉他们 这个案子会变成一个大笑话
The vote is eight to four in favour of guilty.
票数是8比4 「有罪」占优势
What is this? Love Your Underprivileged Brother Week?
这是怎么回事？ 「支持弱势群体周」吗？
I want you to tell me why you changed your vote. Give me reasons.
我要你告诉我为什么要改变心意 快点，给我个理由
I don't have to defend my decision to you. There is a reasonable doubt in my mind.
我没必要向你辩解我的决定 我心里出现了合理的怀疑
Reasonable doubt? Nothing but words. Look at this.
合理的怀疑？不过是句空话 这儿，看看这个
The kid you just decided isn't guilty was seen ramming this into his father!
有人看到你认为无罪的那个孩子 拿这把刀杀了他的父亲
- What about this, Mr Reasonable Doubt? - That's not the knife, remember?
- 你怎么解释，「合理怀疑」先生？ - 这可不是那把凶刀，你还记得吗？
- Oh, brilliant! - I'm tellin' you, this is the craziest.
- 哦，太棒了！ - 我告诉你们，这件事疯狂到头了
I mean, what are we supposed to believe? You're pullin' stories out of thin air.
我们到底应该相信什么？ 你们在凭空编造故事
A guy like this, if he's sittin' ringside at the Dempsey-Firpo fight,
像他这样的家伙，要是看过 丹柏西跟佛波的比赛
he'd be trying to tell you that...
或许他会告诉你们
Look. Now what about the old man?
听着 那老头又是怎么一回事？
Are we supposed to believe he didn't see the kid tearin' down the steps
你要我们假设 他没有在案发后15秒内...
15 seconds after the killing?
跑到大门口吗？
He's just sayin' so to be important, right?
他那么说只是想引人注目 是吗？
- What's the point of it all? - Hold it.
- 这假设到底有什么意义？ - 等一下
The Baltimore rooter is heard from again.
瞧，巴尔的摩队的拉拉队员 开始捧场了
- And pop-ups are fallin' for base hits. - Hold on a second. Look.
- 球员击出安打，拉拉队员就撒纸花 - 等一下。听着...
- Did the old man say he ran to the door? - What's the difference?
- 那个老头说他是跑着到大门口的？ - 他用跑的或是走的又有什么差别？
- He got there, didn't he? - He said he ran. At least I think he did.
- 总之他到了大门口 - 他说他是跑的，至少我想他是这么说的
I don't remember, but I don't see how he could have run.
我记不得了，但是我想 他根本没法跑步
He said he went from his bedroom to the front door. Isn't that enough?
他说他从房间「到了」大门口 这有什么不清楚的吗？
- Where was the bedroom? - Down the hall.
- 他的房间在哪？ - 走廊的尽头
- Don't you remember that? - No.
- 你记得所有细节，却记不得这一点？ - 不记得
- I want to see a diagram of the apartment. - Why don't we have him on trial again?
- 团长先生，我想看看那栋公寓的平面图 - 我们干脆让他们再开一次庭好了
You're the only one wants to see exhibits.
只有你自己想看公寓的平面图
- I want to see this one, too. - I'd like to stop wastin' time.
- 我也想看 - 我不想再浪费时间了
If we're gonna wade through that nonsense about the body...
如果我们继续把时间 浪费在这个...
No, but I'd like to know if an old man who drags one foot cos he had a stroke
这不是浪费时间，我想要知道 一个中风的跛脚老人
can get from his bedroom to his front door in 15 seconds.
能不能在15秒内 从他的房间到大门口
- He said 20. - He said 15.
- 他说是20秒 - 他说是15秒
- 20. What are you tryin' to distort?
- 他说是20秒。你为什么要扭曲事实？
How does he know how long 15 seconds is? You can't judge that.
他怎么会知道15秒到底有多久？ 那种事情谁也没法估计
He said 15. He was positive about it.
他非常肯定地说是15秒
He was an old man! He was confused!
他是个老人 有一半时间都稀里糊涂
How could he be positive about anything?
他怎么能肯定任何事情？
I don't see what you're going to prove. The man said he saw the boy running out.
我看不出你想证明什么 那个老头说他看到那孩子跑出去了
Let's see if the details bear him out. As the body hit the floor,
让我们看看细节能不能支持他的话 当死者摔倒在地后
he said he heard footsteps upstairs, running to the front door.
他说他听到楼上传来脚步声 一路传到了大门口
Heard the upstairs door open, the footsteps start down.
然后听到大门打开的声音 以及下楼的脚步声
He said he got to his own door in, at most, 15 seconds. If the killer ran immediately...
他说他到自己的大门口，至多绝对不超过15秒钟 凶手正好跑开...
- Maybe he didn't. - The old man said he did.
- 也许他并没这么说 - 那老头就是这么说的
You oughta be at that hair-splitters' convention.
你真应该去参加 吹毛求疵大会
Why don't you stop making smart remarks?
你就不能停止自作聪明吗？
My friend, for your three dollars a day, you have to listen to everything.
朋友，为了3块钱一天的陪审团报酬 真是什么鬼话都得听啊，知道吗
Here's the apartment. The old man's was directly beneath and exactly the same.
这是案发现场 老人的房间就在楼下，格局完全一样
Here are the el tracks, the bedroom, living room, kitchen, bathroom, hall, stairs.
这是电车轨道、卧室、客厅 厨房、浴室、走廊、楼梯
The old man was in this bedroom here.
当时老人在这个卧室里
He says he crossed to the door, walked down the hall, opened the door
他说他穿过走廊，径直到了大门口 打开大门
just in time to see the boy running down the stairs. Am I right?
正看见那孩子冲下楼梯 到此为止对吗？
That's the story, for the 19th time.
他一再陈述这样的证词
- 15 seconds after the body hit the floor. - Correct.
- 从听到声音到大门口一共是15秒 - 没错
Now, let's see. It was...
现在让我们来看看，这是...
It's 12 feet from the bed to the door. The hall is 43 feet.
从床到卧室门是12英尺 走廊是43英尺长
He would have had to walk 12 feet, open the bedroom door,
他必须得走上12步 打开卧室门
walk 43 feet down and open the front door, all in 15 seconds.
再走过43英尺的走廊，打开大门 一共不超过15秒钟
- Could he have done it? - Sure.
- 你们觉得他能办到吗？ - 当然可以
He walks slowly. He needed help into the witness chair.
他走起路来非常慢 还要法警扶他上证人席
- You make it sound like a long walk. - For an old man who had a stroke, it is.
- 让你说得这条路好像很远似的 - 对一个中风的老人来说的确很远
- What are you doin'? - I'm gonna try it.
- 你在干嘛？ - 我要试试看
What do you mean? Why didn't his lawyer bring it up?
什么叫你想试试？ 他的律师为什么不试？
- Maybe he just didn't think of it. - Do you think he's an idiot? It's obvious.
- 也许他没有想到这一点 - 你以为他是白痴吗？这太明显了
- Did you think of it? - It don't matter. He didn't bring it up
- 你自己想到这一点了吗？ - 那不重要。他的律师不提出这一点...
because he knew it'd hurt his case.
是因为他知道结果对他很不利
Or because it would have meant bullying and badgering a helpless old man.
也许因为那看起来像是 质疑或是骚扰一个无助的老人
That doesn't sit well with a jury. Most lawyers avoid it.
这会让陪审团不高兴 大部分律师会避免这么做
- What kind of a bum is he? - That's what I'm asking.
- 他到底是个什么样的人？ - 那正是我一直在问的
Pass me that chair. Those two chairs are the old man's bed.
把那张椅子拿给我 那两张椅子代表老人的床
I just paced off 12 feet. This is the bedroom door.
我要恰好量出12英尺距离 这是卧室门
That's crazy. You can't re-create a thing like that.
哦，那太疯狂了 你不能那样重建现场
The hall was 43 feet. I'll pace from that wall and back again.
走廊有43英尺 我要走到那道墙再折回来
This is insane. What are you wasting everybody's time for?
简直是神经病 为什么要浪费大家的时间？
According to you, it'll only take 15 seconds. We can spare that.
根据你的说法，这不过就浪费15秒钟 我们受得了
Come on. Knock it off.
够了，别吹了
OK. OK, OK, killer.
好吧 好，好，怕了你了
Yeah.
好极了
Will you stand there and mark the front door? It was chain-locked, remember.
能站在那里当大门吗？ 别忘了，当时大门上了门链
- Who's got a watch with a second hand? - I have.
- 谁的手表有秒针？ - 我有
Stamp your foot. That'll be the body falling. You can time me from there.
跺一下脚代表死者摔倒 然后你就开始计时
- What are we gonna do, play charades? - What are we waiting for?
- 我们要干嘛，猜拳吗？ - 还等什么？
I wanna wait till the second hand reaches 60.
我想等秒针归零
Aw, come on!
噢，少来了！
Come on, speed it up. He can walk twice as fast as that.
快点，再走快点 那个老人走起来比这快两倍
If you want me to walk faster than that, I will.
如果代表的人是我 当然没问题
- Lock. Door. Stop. - Right.
- 开锁。开门。停 - 好了
What's the time?
多长时间？
Exactly... 41 seconds.
正好...41秒
This is what I think happened. The old man heard the fight a few hours earlier.
我想这才是事实 案发前数小时，老人听到了争吵
When he's in bed, he heard the body hit the floor,
后来他躺在床上 听到有人倒地的声音
heard the woman scream, got to his front door as fast as he could,
他听到那位女士的尖叫 于是拼命赶到大门口看
heard somebody running and assumed it was the boy.
他听到了脚步声 以为是那个孩子
- I think that's possible. - Assumed?
- 我想那是有可能的 - 忽悠！
Brother, I've seen all kinds of dishonesty in my day,
老兄，我这辈子见过 各式各样的骗局
but this little display takes the cake.
数你这段示范最惊人
You all come in here with your hearts bleedin' about slum kids and injustice.
你们带着一腔热血 来这儿同情那些小混混和非正义
You listen to some fairy tales. You start getting through to these old ladies.
你们听到一些神话故事 就开始以为自己理解这些老太婆了
You're not getting through to me. I've had enough.
你们骗不了我
What's the matter with you guys? You all know he's guilty! He's got to burn!
你们这些家伙是怎么了？ 你们都知道那孩子有罪！他应该被丢到火里！
- He'll slip through our fingers. - Slip through our fingers?
- 他迟早要逃出我们的掌心 - 逃出我们的掌心？
- Are you his executioner? - I'm one of 'em.
- 你是他的刽子手吗？ - 我是其中一个
- Perhaps you'd like to pull the switch. - For this kid, you bet I would.
- 也许你想亲自按下电椅开关 - 对于这个孩子，我绝对会
I feel sorry for you. What it must feel like to wanna pull the switch!
我为你感到遗憾 只有疯子才想亲自按下电椅开关！
Ever since you walked in, you've acted like a self-appointed public avenger.
你一走进这里 就一副替天行道的模样
You want to see this boy die because you want it, not because of the facts.
你想看到这孩子死，只是因为私心 而不是因为事实
- You're a sadist. - You...
- 你是个虐待狂 - 你...
Let me go! I'll kill him! I'll kill him!
放开我！我要杀了他 我要杀了他
You don't really mean you'll kill me, do you?
你的意思不会是 真的想「杀了我」吧？
- Anything wrong? I heard some noise. - No, everything's all right.
- 怎么了先生们？我听到吵闹声 - 没什么，一切正常
We're just... Friendly little argument.
我们只是... 一点友好的小争吵
We're through with that diagram. You can take it if you want. Here you are.
我们已经看过了配置图 你可以拿走它了。给你
What are you lookin' at?
你们看什么？
- Somebody has to start off again. - I beg pardon...
- 我想得有人站出来发言 - 抱歉...
"I beg pardon." What are you so polite about?
「抱歉」个毛线啊？ 你这么有礼貌干嘛？
For the same reason you're not. It's the way I was brought up.
就跟你没有礼貌的理由一样 我从小就是个有礼貌的人
This fighting... That's not why we are here, to fight.
吵架... 那不是我们在这里的原因
We have a responsibility.
我们肩负着重大责任
This, I have always thought, is a remarkable thing about democracy.
我一直觉得 这就是我们民主社会的优点
That we are...
我们...
What is the word?
怎么说呢？
Notified. That we are notified by mail to come down to this place
被通知 我们收到信，被通知要来这里...
to decide on the guilt or innocence of a man we... we have never heard of before.
决定一个跟我们 素昧平生的人是否有罪
We have nothing to gain or lose by... by our verdict.
不论做出什么样的判决 我们都拿不到任何好处，也没有任何损失
This is one of the reasons why we are strong.
这就是我们的国家 能这么强大的原因
We should not make it a... personal thing.
我们不应该把这件事 扯上私人感情
If nobody else has an idea, I might have a cutie here.
如果没有人想发言 我有个可爱的主意
Let's throw it out and see if the cat licks it up.
让我们扔掉它 看看猫会不会去舔
- The cat licks it up? - Yeah. The boy...
- 猫去舔它？ - 对。这孩子...
Look how dark it's gettin' out there. I bet we're gonna have a storm now.
看外面天色多暗啊 我看马上就要下大雨了
Boy, oh boy. It's really hot, huh?
天啊，真的好热
- Pardon me, but... don't you ever sweat? - No, I don't.
- 请问...你从不流汗吗？ - 我不流汗
Listen. I... I was wonderin' if...
听着 我...我在想...
Maybe... maybe we should take another vote.
也许...也许我们应该 再投一次票
Great. Maybe we can follow this one up with a little dancing and refreshments!
太棒了。或许接下来我们该跳个舞 吃点东西来庆祝一下!
- Mr Foreman? - Well, that's OK with me.
- 团长先生？ - 好，我没有意见
Anyone doesn't wanna vote? Hey, come on.
有人反对投票吗？ 嘿，别这样
- Sorry. - I think we ought to have an open ballot.
- 噢，对不起 - 我觉得我们应该公开投票
Call out our votes, you know? Let's see who stands where.
表明自己的意愿，知道吗？ 来看看每个人的立场是什么
Well, that sounds fair to me. Anyone object?
好吧，听着挺公平 有人反对吗？
OK. I'll call off your jury numbers. One?
好。我会按照陪审团编号叫大家 一号
Oh, that's me. I vote guilty. Two?
噢，是我 我投「有罪」。二号？
Not guilty.
「无罪」
Number three?
三号？
Guilty.
「有罪」
Number four?
四号？
Number five?
五号？
Not guilty.
「无罪」
Number six?
六号
Number seven?
七号？
Guilty.
「有罪」
Number eight?
八号？
Not guilty.
「无罪」
- Number nine? - Not guilty.
- 九号？ - 「无罪」
- Number ten? - Guilty.
- 十号？ - 「有罪」
Number eleven?
十一号？
Not guilty.
「无罪」
Number twelve?
十二号？
Number twelve!
十二号！
Guilty.
「有罪」
The vote is now six to six.
现在票数是6比6
And we go into extra innings here, eh?
我们要打加时赛了，对吧？
Six to six! I'm telling you, some of you people in here must be out of your minds.
6比6！我告诉你们 你们之中有些人一定是疯了
A kid like that!
像他那样的孩子没救了！
I don't think the kind of boy he is has anything to do with it.
我觉得那孩子像哪样 跟这案子无关
- Facts determine the case. - Don't give me that!
- 事实决定一切 - 少拿那一套来忽悠我
I'm sick and tired of facts. You can twist 'em any way you like.
我厌倦了事实 反正最后事实也会被扭曲，懂吗？
That's exactly the point this gentleman has been making.
那正是这位先生 所强调的重点
You keep shouting at the top of your lungs...
你一直扯着嗓门 对我们大吼大叫...
I'd like to be a few years younger. That man gets on my...
真希望我能年轻个几岁 那家伙害得我...
- My, it's hot in here. - Want a drink of water?
- 天啊，这儿真热 - 喝点水吗？
No, no. Thanks. Thanks.
不，不了 谢谢。谢谢
- It's gonna rain. - Well, how'd you figure that out, killer?
- 快下雨了 - 你怎么知道？大天才
- How come you changed your vote? - It just seemed there was room for doubt.
- 你为什么要改变投票？ - 这个案子看来确实有值得怀疑的地方
- You haven't got a leg to stand on. - I don't feel that way.
- 你根本就是墙头草 - 我不那么认为
- A lot of details never came out. - Yeah, well, good luck.
- 很多细节并没有查清楚 - 好极了，那么，祝你好运
Come on. You're like everybody else. You think too much, you get mixed up.
少来了，你跟其他人一样 想得太多反而迷糊了
- You know what I mean? - I don't think you have any right to...
- 懂不懂？ - 我不认为你有权利...
Loudmouth.
大嗓门
Look at that come down, will ya?
看看这场大雨
You know, this reminds me of a storm we had last...
知道吗，这让我想起 之前遇到的一场雨...
Was it November? I don't know. Something.
那是十一月的事吗？ 我不知道，可能吧
It was quite a storm we had. It was right in the middle of a game.
那场雨下得真大 正好在球赛进行到一半时
We were behind-seven to six. We'd just started to move the ball, made a tackle.
我们以6比7落后 由我们来进攻
It was gonna cut right in, slash through, slashed right in, cut right through...
做了一个漂亮的擒抱 开始往右路切入，一路往前冲...
And...
而且...
We had this kid - Slattery.
队里有个孩子 史拉特利
He was an ox. A real ox.
他就像头牛 一头真正的牛
I wish I had another one just like him.
我巴不得能找到 另一个跟他一模一样的球员
I forgot to tell you. I'm the assistant head coach at Andrew J McCorkle High School.
我忘了告诉你。我是安德鲁麦柯克高中 助理总教练
That's out in Queens.
那所学校在皇后区
And anyway... we're starting to move along real nice.
总之... 我们的进攻非常顺利
You know, their whole line is just... just comin' apart.
知道吗，对手的整个防线... 马上就要崩溃了
And it starts to come down, cats and dogs, just like this.
然后突然就下起了大雨 雨势就跟这场雨一样大
Just... whoosh! You know, right down.
马上就...哗！你知道吗，简直
Well, it was murder, you know?
那真是要人命 你知道吗？
I swear, I... I nearly bawled. Just... We couldn't go nowhere.
我发誓，我...我差点要疯了 马上就...我们真是一点办法都没有
Hey, what is it with this fan here? How come...
嘿，这电扇到底是怎么一回事？ 怎么会...
Must have been on the same switch with the lights.
看来是要 从电灯的开关启动
Well, things are lookin' up here, huh?
好吧，局势开始好转了 对吧？
Yeah.
没错
Boy, that's better.
天啊，凉快多了
Hey! Two points.
嘿！两分
You guys ever go to the Garden?
你们去过花园广场吗？
That's a damn stupid thing to do.
那么做真是太蠢了
Oh, I'm sorry. I...
哦，我很抱歉 我...
You know?
你知道吗？
Pardon me.
借过
Well, how do you like it? Even-steven. Pretty surprising, isn't it?
你觉得如何呢？现在是平分 令人大跌眼镜吧？
Yes.
是的
That... business before, when that tall guy, whatshisname, was tryin' to bait me?
那个...之前的事，那个叫什么的高个儿 想要引我上钩
That doesn't prove anything. I'm a... pretty excitable person.
那无法证明任何事 我是个...很容易激动的人
Where does he come off calling me a public avenger, a sadist?
他凭什么说我想替天行道 还是个虐待狂？
Anyone in his right mind would blow his stack.
头脑清醒的人 也可以发脾气
He was just tryin' to bait me.
他只是想引我上钩
He did an excellent job.
他做得很好
I think we're going nowhere here.
我告诉你们我怎么想的 我们什么结论也得不出了
I'm ready to walk into court and declare a hung jury.
我准备到法庭宣布 本案将成为悬判
- There's no point in this thing going on. - I go for that, too.
- 没必要再继续讨论下去了 - 我也赞成
Let the kid take his chance with 12 other guys.
让这孩子 到下一批陪审团手里碰运气吧
The judge won't accept a hung jury. We haven't been here long.
我们才刚讨论了不久 法官是不会同意悬判的
- Well, let's find out. - I am not in favour of that.
- 是吗，咱们走着瞧吧 - 我不打算那么做
This kid wouldn't stand a chance with another jury, and you know it.
你知道把本案交给下一批陪审团 这孩子是死路一条
Come on, we're hung. Nobody's gonna change his vote.
快点吧，我们早陷入僵局了 没有人打算改变自己的投票
- Still no room for reasonable doubt? - No.
- 仍然没发现合理的怀疑？ - 没有
Pardon. Maybe you don't fully understand the term "reasonable doubt".
对不起，也许你不了解 「合理怀疑」的意思
What do you mean, I don't understand?
你是什么意思 什么叫我不了解？
How do you like this guy? I'm tellin' you, they're all alike.
你认为这家伙怎么样？ 我告诉你，他们全都一个样子
They come over here and before they can take a breath,
他们来到这里 气都没喘匀
they're telling us how to run the show.
就急着告诉我们 该怎么做出判决
- Boy, the arrogance of this guy! - All right.
- 老天，这家伙太傲慢了！ - 好了
Let's stop the arguing for about two minutes in here.
请大家暂时 停止争吵
Now, who's got something constructive to say?
现在，谁想发表 有建设性的意见？
I'd like to go over something, if you gentlemen don't mind.
如果大家不介意的话 我有些话想说
An important point for the prosecution was
对检方来说 有件事非常重要...
the fact that after the boy claimed he was at the movies when the killing took place,
也就是那孩子说 他案发时正在电影院里
he couldn't remember the names of the movies or who starred in them.
但他却记不得那部电影的名字 也说不出演员的名字
- This gentleman has made that point. - That's correct.
- 刚才这位先生提到了这点 - 没错
It's the only alibi the boy offered, and he couldn't back it up with any details.
那是被告提出的唯一不在场证明 但他却无法说明所有细节
In the boy's place, do you think you could remember details
如果你是那个孩子 在被父亲扇耳光后
after an upsetting experience such as being slapped by your father?
心烦意乱中 还能记得电影细节吗？
I think so, if there were any special details to remember.
我觉得可以 只要这些细节很特别
The boy couldn't remember the movies because he wasn't there.
那孩子什么都记不起来 因为他根本就不在电影院
According to the police testimony, the boy was questioned in the kitchen,
根据警方证词 这孩子是在厨房被询问的
while the body of his father was lying in the bedroom.
当时他父亲的尸体 还躺在地板上
Do you think you could remember details?
那种情况下 你还能记得电影细节？
- I do. - Under great emotional stress?
- 我可以 - 在那么大的精神压力下？
- Under great emotional stress. - He remembered them correctly in court.
- 一点都没错 - 他在法庭上就正确回忆出了所有细节
Yes. His lawyer took great pains to bring that out.
对，他的律师费足了劲儿 才让他说出来
He had three months to the day of the trial in which to memorise them.
从案发到接受审判 他有3个月时间回想细节
It's not difficult for a lawyer to find out what played on a particular night.
要查出那天放映了哪部电影 并不难
I'll take the testimony from right after the murder,
我只认可案发后他第一次说的证词
when he couldn't remember a thing about the movies, great emotional stress or not.
也就是他说记不起电影所有的细节 不论他是不是承受了巨大的精神压力
- I'd like to ask you a personal question. - Go ahead.
- 我想问你一个私人问题 - 请便
- Where were you last night? - I was home all night.
- 昨晚你在哪儿？ - 我整晚在家
- How about the night before that? - What is this?
- 前天晚上呢？ - 这是干嘛？
It's all right. I left the office at 8.30 and went straight home and to bed.
没关系。我八点半下班 然后就直接回家睡觉了
- And the night before that? - That was... Tuesday night.
- 大前天晚上呢？ - 那是...星期二晚上
- The bridge tournament. I played bridge. - Monday night?
- 桥牌比赛。我去打桥牌了 - 星期一晚上呢？
When you get to New Year's Eve 1954, let me know.
回想到1954年除夕之夜时 再来叫我
Monday night? Monday night... my wife and I went to the movies.
周一晚上？周一晚上... 我和我太太看电影去了
- What did you see? - The Scar/et Circ/e. A whodunit.
- 你们看了哪部电影？ - 《The Scarlet Circle》，侦探片
- What was the second feature? - The...
- 附赠的二流电影叫什么名字？ - The...
I'll tell you in a minute. The...
我马上告诉你 The...
Remarkab/e Mrs...
Remarkable Mrs...
Something.
诸如此类
Mrs Bainbridge. The Remarkab/e Mrs Bainbridge.
Mrs Bainbridge. The Remarkable Mrs Bainbridge.
I saw that. It's called The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge.
我看过那部电影 它叫做《The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge》
Yes. The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge.
哦对，《The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge》 我想是的
Who was in The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge?
里面都有哪些演员？
Barbara... Long, I think it was.
芭芭拉...隆格，我想是她
A dark, very pretty girl.
一个漂亮的黑美人
- Ling or... Long. Something like that. - Who else?
- 不是林德就是隆格，大概姓这个 - 还有谁？
I'd never heard of them before.
其他人我从来没听过
It was a very inexpensive second feature, with unknown...
这是一部低成本二流电影 请了名不见经传...
And you weren't under an emotional stress, were you?
你当时并没有承受 巨大的精神压力吧？
No.
没...
I wasn't.
没有
- I think the point is made. - Big point.
- 我想大家都清楚重点了 - 好大的重点
You can talk till your tongue is draggin' on the floor. The boy is guilty.
你爱怎么说就怎么说 那孩子还是有罪
Know what I mean, my friend?
懂不懂，我的朋友？
- You got those cough drops? - They're all gone, my friend.
- 你还有喉糖吗？ - 已经吃完了，我的朋友
Oh, boy. Look at that rain. There goes your ball game.
天啊，雨下的还真大 看来你的球赛该取消了
It's only a shower.
这只是一场阵雨
Besides, they got the infield covered.
而且内野一定会盖上防水布
Say, could I see that knife a second, please?
我说，能让我再看看那把刀吗？
Well, we're still tied up six to six. Who's got a suggestion?
现在票数还是6比6平手 有人有任何建议吗？
- It's 5 after 6. Let's get some dinner. - Why don't we wait till 7 o'clock?
- 现在6点过5分，去吃晚饭吧 - 7点再说吧，再等一小时
OK with me.
我没意见
There's something I'd like to say. It's been bothering me a little,
有件事我想说 这件事一直让我很困惑
and as long as we're stuck...
反正我们被困在这里...
There was this whole business about the stab wound and how it was made.
对于死者致命伤的伤口 我一直觉得不对劲
- The downward angle of it, you know? - Don't start with that again.
- 你知道吗，伤口的角度向下 - 你又来了
- They've been over it and over it. - I know, but I don't go along with it.
- 律师们已经反复讨论过了 - 我知道，但我就是觉得不对劲
The boy was five feet seven inches tall. His father was six two.
那孩子5英尺7英寸高 他父亲是6英尺2英寸
That's a difference of seven inches.
他们的身高相差7英寸
It's very awkward to stab down into the chest of someone over half a foot taller.
要往下刺一个比你高半英尺的人 不是一件简单事
Give me that.
给我刀
I'll give you a demonstration. Somebody get up.
我演示给你们看 哪位站出来
Watch this - I don't wanna have to do it again.
看好了 我懒得再演示一次
I'll make myself about six or seven inches shorter.
我会往下蹲 让自己比他矮上7英寸
- That's about right. Maybe a little more. - OK, a little more.
- 差不多，可能还得再低点 - 好，再低一点
Now... nobody's hurt.
好了... 没有人会受伤
- Right? - Right. Nobody hurt.
- 对吗？ - 对。没有人会受伤
Now, this is the way I'd stab a man who was... taller than I was.
我就是这样 刺伤比我高的人
Look at the angle. Down and in.
看看这个角度 是向下压的
And this is the way it was done. Now tell me I'm wrong.
他就是这么干的 有本事指出我错了
- Down and in. There's no argument. - Hold on a minute.
- 角度下压，没错了 - 等一下
Will you give me that?
请把刀给我
Boy, I hate these things.
天啊，我恨透这些事了
- Did you ever see a knife fight? - No.
- 你看过别人互砍吗？ - 没有
Anybody here ever see a knife fight?
有人看过别人互砍吗？
Well, I have. You know, on my back stoop, the lot across the street, back yard.
我看过。当时我蜷着身子 他们在对街后院里械斗
Switchblades came with the neighbourhood.
在我的社区里 拥有折叠刀并稀罕
Funny I never thought of it before. I guess you try to forget.
有趣的是我以前从来没注意过 我一直努力忘了它
- How do you use a switchblade? - Well, you'd never use it like this.
- 你会怎么使用折叠刀？ - 没人会这样使用折叠刀
See, you'd lose too much time switching hands.
看，这样亮出刀子 太浪费时间
Here's how. Underhand.
应该这样 正手持刀
Anyone who's ever used one wouldn't handle it any other way.
任何用折叠刀的人 都是这个姿势
- Are you sure? - I'm sure.
- 你确定？ - 我非常确定
- It's why they're made to open like that. - The boy was pretty handy with a knife?
- 所以折叠刀才做成这样 - 这孩子是用刀的高手？
You think he could have made the wound that killed his father?
你觉得他会反手持刀 杀死他父亲吗？
No. Not with the experience he got all his life handling these things.
不可能，除非专门练习 他不可能反手持刀
- I feel he'd have gone for him underhand. - How do you know?
- 我想他杀人会用正手持刀的 - 你怎么知道？
- Were you there when he was killed? - No. Neither was anybody else.
- 你当时在场吗？ - 不，当时没有人在场
What are you giving us this mumbo jumbo for? I don't believe it.
你凭什么告诉我们这些 凭空杜撰的事？我不信
I don't think you can tell what wound he might have made
我不认为你猜的出 那孩子是怎么杀人的
simply because he knew how to handle a knife.
因为他太清楚如何使用刀子了
- What do you think? - I don't know.
- 你觉得呢？ - 我不知道
- What do you mean, you don't know?
- 你什么意思？你不知道？ - 我就是不知道
- How about you? - I don't know about the rest of 'em,
- 你呢？ - 我不知道其他人怎么想的
but I'm gettin' tired of this yakety-yakkin'. It's gettin' us nowhere.
但我已经厌倦了这一切 什么结论也得不出
So I guess /'// have to break it up. I'm changin' my vote to not guilty.
我想我要做出突破 我要改变决定，投「无罪」一票
- You're what? - You heard me. I've had enough.
- 你说什么？ - 你都听到了，我受够了
- You've had enough? That's no answer. - Listen, you just take care of yourself.
- 你受够了？那不是答案！ - 听着，你搞定自己就好了
- You know? - He's right.
- 知道吗？ - 他说的对
That's not an answer.
那不是答案
What kind of a man are you?
你到底是个什么样的人？
You have sat here and voted guilty with everyone else
你刚刚还坐在这儿 跟大家一样投了「有罪」一票
because there are some baseball tickets burning a hole in your pocket.
只因为兜里的破球票 烧得你心急火燎
Now you have changed your vote because you say you're sick of all the talking?
现在你就改变了主意 说你厌倦了这些讨论？
- Now, listen, buddy... - Who tells you that you have the right
- 听说我，兄弟... - 谁告诉你说你有权利...
to play like this with a man's life? Don't you care...
这样子玩弄他人的生命？ 你不在乎吗...
Now, wait a minute. You can't talk like that to me.
等一下 你不能那样子跟我说话
I can talk like that to you. If you want to vote not guilty,
我当然可以那样子跟你说话 如果你要投「无罪」一票
do it because you are convinced he is not guilty, not because you've had enough.
必须是你真的相信被告无罪 而不是因为你觉得厌烦
And if you think he is guilty, then vote that way.
如果你觉得他有罪 你必须坚持下去
Or don't you have the guts to do what you think is right?
难道你没有种 去做你认为对的事情吗？
- Now, listen... - Guilty or not guilty?
- 听着... - 有罪还是无罪？
- I told you. Not guilty. - Why?
- 我已经说了，无罪 - 为什么？
- Look, I don't have to... - You do have to. Say it. Why?
- 听着，我不必... - 你非说出来不可，为什么？
I... I don't think he's guilty.
我...我不觉得他有罪
- I want another vote. - OK, that's another vote called for.
- 我要求再一次投票 - 好的，有人要求再投一次票
I guess the quickest way is a show of hands. Anyone object?
我想最快的方法是举手表决 有人反对吗？
OK, all those voting not guilty, raise your hands.
好，认为被告「无罪」的人 请举手
One, two, three,
一、二、三
four, five, six, seven...
四、五、六、七...
eight.
八
Nine.
九
All those voting guilty, raise your hands.
认为被告「有罪」的人 请举手
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Well, the vote's nine to three in favour of acquittal.
好了，票数是9比3 无罪的一方占优势
I don't understand you people!
我搞不清你们这些人！
All these picky little points you keep bringing up, they don't mean nothing!
你们提出的那些细节 根本什么都说明不了
You saw this kid just like I did.
你们跟我都看到了那个孩子
Don't tell me you believe that phoney story about losing the knife
别跟我说你们相信 刀子丢失的鬼话
and about being at the movies.
还有案发时在看电影的说词
Look, you know how these people lie. It's born in them.
听着，你们知道这些人爱撒谎 那是他们天生的劣根性
What the heck? I don't have to tell you. They don't know what the truth is!
见鬼，不用我来告诉你们 他们根本不知道什么是事实！
And they don't need any real big reason to kill someone, either.
而且他们杀人 根本不需要什么理由
No, sir. They get drunk. They're real big drinkers, all of 'em.
一点不需要。他们喝醉了 全都烂醉如泥
You know that. And bang! Someone's lying in the gutter.
你懂的。然后「砰」 有人倒在水沟里
Nobody's blaming 'em. That's the way they are by nature.
没有人会怪他们 那就是他们天生的劣根性
You know what I mean? Violent. Where are you going?
知道我指的是什么吗？天生的暴力倾向 你要去哪儿？
Human life don't mean as much to them as it does to us.
他们对人命的看法 跟我们完全不同
They're lushing it up and fighting all the time,
他们总是扭打成一团
and if somebody gets killed, somebody gets killed! They don't care!
就算有人死了， 就算有人死了！他们也不在乎
Sure, there's some good things about 'em, too. I'm the first one to say that.
当然了，他们中间也是有好人的 我会第一个这么说
I've known a couple who were OK, but that's the exception.
我认识一两个还不错的混混 但那是例外
Most of 'em, it's like they have no feelings! They can do anything!
他们中的大多数，毫无感情 什么事都干得出来
What's going on here?
这是怎么一回事？
I'm trying to tell you. You're making a big mistake, you people.
我正试着告诉你们 你们犯了大错，你们这些人
This kid is a liar. I know it. I know all about them.
那孩子是个骗子，我知道 我太了解那些人了
Listen to me. They're no good.
听我说 他们之中没有好人
There's not a one of 'em who's any good.
连一个好人也没有
I mean, what's happening in here?
我是说 这到底是怎么一回事？
I speak my piece, and you...
我说出我的想法 而你们...
Listen to me.
听我说
I... We're... we're...
我... 我们... 我们...
This kid on trial here. His type. Well, don't you know about them?
被告是个小混混 难道你们不了解他们那种人吗？
There's a... There's a danger here.
他们是... 他们是危险人物
These people are dangerous.
他们极度危险
They're... wild.
他们... 很疯狂
Listen to me. Listen to me.
听我说。听我说
I have. Now, sit down and don't open your mouth again.
我听着呢。现在请你坐下 把嘴巴闭上
Some of the time... I tell you.
有时候... 我告诉你...
It's always difficult to keep personal prejudice out of a thing like this.
每当面对这种事 要排除个人偏见真的很难
Wherever you run into it, prejudice always obscures the truth.
不论在哪儿碰到 偏见总是遮蔽了真相
I don't really know what the truth is.
我真的不知道真相是什么
I don't suppose anybody will ever really know.
我想没有任何人 真的知道真相是什么
Nine of us now seem to feel that the defendant is innocent.
我们9个人现在只是感觉 被告是无辜的
But we're just gambling on probabilities. We may be wrong.
但是我们是在赌一个可能性 或许我们错了
We may be trying to let a guilty man go free. I don't know. Nobody really can.
我们或许会放走一个杀人犯 我不知道。没有人知道
But we have a reasonable doubt.
但我们有合理的怀疑
And that's something that's very valuable in our system.
那是我们司法制度中 非常珍贵的一部分
No jury can declare a man guilty unless it's sure.
除非确定无疑 陪审团无法判决被告有罪
We nine can't understand how you three are still so sure.
我们9个人不明白 为什么你们3个人到现在还那么确定
- Maybe you can tell us. - I'll try.
- 也许你们能告诉我们 - 我会的
You've made some excellent points, but I still believe the boy is guilty.
你的确提出了一些精彩的论点 但我还是相信那孩子有罪...
I have two reasons. One: The evidence given by the woman across the street,
原因有二。一、街对面那位女士的证词
who actually saw the murder committed.
那位女士看到了谋杀
That's the most important testimony.
那是最重要的证词
And two: The fact that she described the stabbing
二、她描述出了案发过程
by saying she saw the boy raise his arm over his head
她说她看到那个孩子 双手持刀高举过头
and stab down into the father's chest.
然后往他父亲胸口刺下
- She saw him do it, the wrong way. - That's absolutely right.
- 她看到他愤怒地杀了人 - 一点没错
Let's talk about this woman for a moment.
我们来谈谈这位女士
She said she went to bed about eleven o'clock that night.
她说案发当晚 大约在11点上床睡觉
Her bed was next to the window, and she could look out
她的床就在窗户边 只要往外一看...
and see directly into the boy's room across the street.
就可以看到 街对面那孩子的房间
She tossed and turned for over an hour.
她辗转反侧大约一小时
Finally, she turned toward the window at about 10 minutes after 12,
最后，大约在12点10分 她转身面向窗户...
and as she looked out, she saw the killing through the windows of a passing el train.
她往外一看，透过电车车窗 看到杀人的经过
She said the lights went out after the killing,
她说案发时四周一片漆黑...
but that she got a good look at the boy in the act of stabbing his father.
但她清清楚楚地看到 那孩子拿刀刺向他父亲
As far as I can see it, this is unshakeable testimony.
在我的看法里 这项证词牢不可破
- Well, that's the whole case. - What do you think?
- 对了，就是这么回事 - 你觉得呢？
How about you?
你呢？
I don't know. So much evidence to sift. This is a pretty complicated business.
我不知道。很多证词有待调查 这个案子很复杂
Frankly, I don't see how you can vote for acquittal.
老实说，我不明白 你为什么会认为他无罪？
- It's not so easy to arrange the evidence. - Throw out all the other evidence!
- 要逐个讨论各证据并不容易 - 你可以抛开其他证据！
The woman saw him do it! What else do you want?
那位女士看到他了 你还要什么样的证据？
- Well, maybe... - Let's vote on it.
- 也许... - 我们对此投票吧
OK, there's another vote called for. Anyone object?
好，有人要求再度投票 有谁反对吗？
All right. I'm changing my vote.
好吧，我改变主意了
- He's guilty. - Anybody else? The vote is eight to four.
- 他有罪 - 其他人呢？现在票数8比4
Why is this such a personal triumph for you, this one vote?
你那么得意干嘛？ 只是一票
OK. I say we're a hung jury. I say we take it in to the judge.
好吧，我说过此案会变成悬判 就这样告诉法官吧
How about it? I wanna hear arguments.
怎么样？ 我要听听大家的意见
You, you're the leader of the cause. What about it?
你，都是你惹出来的 你觉得怎么样？
- Let's go over it again. - We've been over it again.
- 我们再讨论一遍 - 我们已经讨论N遍了！
The boy in the grey flannel suit is bouncin' back and forth like a tennis ball.
这个穿着灰色绒布外套的孩子 像个网球一样被我们击来打去
There's no point in getting nasty. You keep trying to turn this into a contest.
没必要说的这么恶心 你老是把这件事看得像场竞赛
OK.
好吧
Maybe we can talk about setting some kind of time limit.
或许我们该定个最后期限
Yeah. Once around for the deal, huh?
好。时间一到就下结论，如何？
It's... a quarter after six. Someone before mentioned seven o'clock.
现在是...6点15分 之前有人提过7点要吃晚餐
That's a point at which we might begin to discuss whether we're a hung jury or not.
我们就讨论到7点 不论这个案子最终会不会悬判
- Don't you feel well? - I feel perfectly well, thank you.
- 你不舒服吗？ - 我很好，谢谢
I was saying seven o'clock would be a reasonable time...
我觉得7点钟 是一个合理的时间...
The reason I asked that was because you were rubbing your nose like...
我会那么说是因为 你一直在按摩鼻子...
Oh, I'm sorry for interrupting.
哦，抱歉打断一下
But you made a gesture that reminded me of something.
你的动作让我 想起了一件事
- I'm trying to settle something here. - Well, I think this is important.
- 我正试着帮大家解决难题 - 但是，我要说的内容很重要
Thank you. Now, then. I'm sure you'll pardon me for this,
谢谢。我相信 你会原谅我这么说...
but I was wondering why you rub your nose like that.
我一直在想 为什么你要那样按摩鼻子
Come on, will you?
少来了
At this point I happen to be talking to the gentleman sitting next to you.
我现在是在跟 你边上的先生说话
Now, why were you rubbing your nose like that?
为什么你要那样按摩鼻子？
If it's any of your business, I was rubbing it because it bothers me a little.
我这么做是因为鼻子不舒服 如果这跟你有什么关系的话
Oh, I'm sorry. Is it... Is it because of your eyeglasses?
哦，对不起 是因为你戴眼镜的原因吗？
It is. Now could we get on to something else?
没错 现在我们可以谈点别了吗？
Your eyeglasses made those two deep impressions on the sides of your nose.
你的眼镜在鼻梁侧面 压出那些很深的印子
I hadn't noticed that before. That must be annoying.
我之前没注意到 那肯定不舒服
It is very annoying.
是很不舒服
I wouldn't know about that. I've never worn eyeglasses. 20/20.
我不了解那种感受 我从不戴眼镜。2.0 / 2.0
Listen, will you come on already with the optometrist bit?
听着，请你别谈这些 眼科医生才关心的事，好吗？
The woman who testified that she saw the killing
出庭作证 说看到凶案的那位女士...
had those same marks on the sides of her nose.
鼻梁侧面 也有同样的印子
Holy smoke! He's right.
老天！他说的对
Please. Just give me a minute... and I'll be finished.
请安静。再给我一点时间 让我把话说完
I don't know if anyone else noticed that about her.
我不知道其他人 是否注意到她
I didn't think of it then, but I've been going over her face... in my mind.
那时我并没在意 但我脑海中一直浮现她的脸庞
She had those same marks. She kept rubbing them in court.
她脸上也有同样的印子 她在法庭上也一直在按摩鼻子
He's right. She did do that a lot.
她说的对。她的确常那么做
This woman was about 45 years old.
这位女士大约45岁
She was making a tremendous effort to look 35.
她很努力让自己 看起来只有35岁
For her first public appearance. Heavy make-up. Dyed hair.
她化了浓妆，染了头发...
Brand-new clothes that should have been worn by a younger woman.
穿上年轻女孩 才会穿的新衣服
No glasses. Well, women do that. See if you can get a mental picture of her.
她没戴着眼镜。女人常那么做 你们应该能了解她们的心态
What do you mean, no glasses? How do you know whether she wore glasses?
没戴着眼镜？你什么意思？ 你怎么知道她戴眼镜？
- Just cos she was rubbin' her nose? - She had those marks. I saw 'em.
- 就因为她按摩鼻子吗？ - 她脸上有那种印子。我看到了
- So? What do you think that means? - I'm sick of your yellin'...
- 所以呢？那又说明什么？ - 我受够了你的大吼大叫...
Come on. Forget it.
好了，别在意
Hey, listen. Listen, he's right. I saw them too. I was the closest one to her.
嘿，听着，他说的对，我也看到了 我是最靠近她的人
She had these things on the side of her nose.
她鼻子侧面也有这些东西
What point are you makin'?
你想证明什么？
She had dyed hair, marks on her nose. What does that mean?
她染了头发，鼻子上有印子 这有什么意义？
Could those marks be made by anything other than eyeglasses?
这些印子可能是眼镜之外 其他东西造成的吗？
No. They couldn't.
不，不可能
I didn't see any marks!
我没看到任何印子！
I did. Strange, but I didn't think about it before.
我看到了。奇怪的是， 我之前并没有想到这点
Why didn't the lawyer say something?
为什么律师没有提出质疑？
There are twelve people in here concentrating on this case.
这房间里有12个人
- Eleven of us didn't think of it either. - What about the district attorney?
- 其中11个人也没有想到这点 - 那检察官呢？
You think he'd pull that? Have her testify without her glasses?
你觉得他让她 在出庭时摘掉了眼镜吗？
Ever see a woman who didn't want to wear them because they spoil her looks?
有些女人不喜欢戴眼镜 那会使她们看起来丑
OK. She had marks on her nose. I'm givin' you that.
好吧，她鼻子上有印子 我承认这点
From glasses, right? She didn't wanna wear 'em out of the house
那是眼镜造成的，对吧？ 她不想戴眼镜
so people'd think she's gorgeous.
那会在别人面前显得漂亮
But when she saw this kid killin' his father, she was in the house alone.
但她看到那孩子杀他父亲时 没有别人在她房间里
That's all.
就是那样
Do you wear glasses when you go to bed?
你会戴着眼镜睡觉吗？
No. I don't.
不，不会
No one wears eyeglasses to bed.
没人会戴着眼镜睡觉
It's logical to assume that she wasn't wearing them in bed.
我们可以合理地推测 她睡觉时并没戴眼镜
- How do you know? - I don't know. I'm guessing.
- 你怎么知道？ - 我不知道，那是我猜的
I'm also guessing that she didn't put them on when she looked out of the window.
我还猜测她往窗外看时 没戴着眼镜
She testified the killing took place just as she looked out.
她作证说 案发后她立即就往窗外看
The lights went off. She didn't have time to put them on.
电灯是关着的 她根本没时间戴眼镜
Here's another guess. She honestly thought she saw the boy kill his father.
我还猜测， 她真以为她看到那孩子杀他父亲
- I say she only saw a blur. - How do you know what she saw?
- 要我说她只看到一个影子 - 你怎么知道她看到什么了？
How does he know all that? How do you know what glasses she wore?
你怎么知道那些？ 你怎么知道她戴的是哪种眼镜？
Maybe they were sunglasses! Maybe she was far-sighted! What do you know?
或许是太阳镜！或许是老花镜！ 你怎么知道？
I only know the woman's eyesight is in question now.
我只知道那女人的视力 现在成了争议
She had to be able to identify a person 60 feet away, at night, without glasses.
她得在昏暗的夜色中不戴眼镜 辨识出60尺外的人
You can't send someone off to die on evidence like that.
只靠这样的证据 你不能让一个人坐电椅
Aw, don't give me that.
噢，少来这一套
- Might she not have made a mistake? - No.
- 不可能是她看错了吗？ - 不可能
- It's not possible? - No, it's not possible.
- 这不可能吗？ - 不，绝不可能
Is it possible?
这有可能吗？
Not guilty.
无罪
Do you think he's guilty?
你觉得他有罪吗？
I think he's guilty.
我觉得他有罪
Do you?
你呢？
No.
无罪
I'm convinced. Not guilty.
我被说服了，他无罪
- What's the matter with you? - I have a reasonable doubt now.
- 你是怎么了？ - 我现在有了合理的怀疑
- It's eleven to one. - What about all the other evidence?
- 现在是11比1 - 其他证据又是怎么一回事？
What about all that stuff? The... The knife? The whole business?
关于其他证据呢？ 刀？其他的一切？
Well, you said we could throw out all the other evidence.
你刚才说过我们可以抛开 其他的证据
Well, what do we do now?
那么，现在我们怎么办？
You're alone.
你孤身一人了
I don't care whether I'm alone or not. It's my right.
我不在乎是不是孤军奋战 这是我的权利
It's your right.
这是你的权利
Well, what do you want? I say he's guilty.
好吧，你想怎么办？ 我说他有罪
- We want to hear your arguments. - I gave you my arguments.
- 我们要听听你的说法 - 该说的我都说了
We're not convinced. We want to hear them again.
我们没被说服 我们要再听一次
We have as much time as it takes.
我们有的是时间
Everything-every single thing that took place in that courtroom says he's guilty.
所有的证据 法庭上所有的证词都证明他有罪
What do you think? I'm an idiot or somethin'?
你们以为呢？ 难道我是白痴吗？
Take that stuff about the old man, who lived there and heard everything!
为什么不相信那个老头说的话！ 楼下的老人听到了一切！
Or this business about the knife. They found another one exactly like it?
还有那把刀 他们找到了跟它一模一样的？
The old man saw him! Right there, on the stairs.
那老人看到他了！ 就在楼梯上
What's the difference how many seconds it was?
他到底花了几秒钟跑到楼梯口 那又有什么差别？
Every single thing. The knife fallin' through a hole in his pocket.
所有的证据 刀子从他口袋的破洞掉了出去
You can't prove he didn't get to the door!
你不能证明他没有夺门而出！
Sure, you can take all the time, hobble around the room, but you can't prove it!
你可以量时间，蹒跚地走来走去 但你无法证明那一点
And what about this business of the el? And the movies?
电车又是怎么一回事？ 还有电影院呢？
There's a phoney deal if I ever heard one.
我非常确定 那都是他编出来的谎话
I'll bet you $5,000 /'d remember the movies I saw.
我跟你赌5千块 我记得住我看过的电影
I'm tellin' you, everything that's gone on has been twisted and turned!
我告诉你们 所有事实都被扭曲了
This business with the glasses? How do you know she didn't have 'em on?
关于眼睛的说词？ 你怎么知道当时她没戴眼镜？
This woman testified in open court!
这位女士已经在法庭上作证了！
And what about hearin' the kid yell? Huh?
还有那孩子的喊叫声呢？嗯？
I'm tellin' ya, I've got all the facts here.
我告诉你们 我知道什么才是事实
Here...
好了...
Well, that's it. That's the whole case.
够了，这就是全部事实
Well?
怎么着？
Say something!
说话啊！
You lousy bunch of bleedin' hearts.
你们这群狠心的混蛋
You're not gonna intimidate me. I'm entitled to my opinion.
你们无法威胁我 我要坚持我的看法
Rotten kids... You work your life out!
死孩子，你毁了自己的一生
No...
不...
Not guilty.
无罪
We're ready now.
我们准备好了
Hey!
嘿！
- What's your name? - Davis.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 戴维斯
My name's McCardle.
我叫迈卡迪
- Well, so long. - So long.
- 那么，再会 - 再会